<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>High Energy on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/high-energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in High Energy on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/high-energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfredo Chicken Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/alfredo-chicken-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/alfredo-chicken-pasta/</guid>
      <description>This high-calorie meal is perfect to refuel after a long day of adventuring. Tasty and filling, without being overly heavy. Try it and you&amp;rsquo;ll adopt it!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) dry macaroni ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried broccoli ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried chicken ⅓ cup (80 ml) shelf-stable shredded parmesan 3 tbsp (45 ml) heavy cream powder ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Curry Rice Vermicelli</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</guid>
      <description>This one-pot recipe is rich in flavors and in carbohydrates! It will provide the energy needed to recharge the batteries in prevision for a long day of backpacking.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 oz (90g) thin rice vermicelli ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried mixed vegetables ¼ cup (60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight High-Calorie Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</guid>
      <description>The perfect comfort food, this mac&amp;amp;cheese is creamy, rich and made with real (freeze dried) cheddar cheese. When calorie needs are high and space limited in your packs, don&amp;rsquo;t look further!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) macaroni ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried chives ¼ cup (60 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Alfredo Gnocchi</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavor (and in calories!), this recipe is perfect for these difficult overnight backpacking trips.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 package of 17.6 oz (500g) gnocchi 3.25 oz. (92g) pre-cooked bacon 1 can 7.6 fl. oz. (225 ml) table cream (I used Table Cream by Nestlé) 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried chives 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried parsley ⅓ cup (80 ml) parmigiano reggiano, shredded ¼ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>