<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Peppercorn and Orange Candied Pecans</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pink-peppercorn-orange-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pink-peppercorn-orange-pecans/</guid>
      <description>This spicy and sweet seasoning is so addictive! If you are able to refain from eating them all before heading to the outdoors, this snack made of nuts will provide energy during long low-intensity outdoor activities. They also make great gifts!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pecans (whole or halves) 1½ cup (22.5 ml) honey 1 tbsp (15 ml) pink peppercorns, slightly crushed 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Holiday Gift Ideas for Gourmet Hikers</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/holiday-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/holiday-gifts/</guid>
      <description>Are you still looking for holiday gift ideas for your favorite gourmet hiker? Don’t look any further, check out this top 10 holiday gift ideas under 35$.
Note: This blog post contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
Cooking Stuff Spork A combination of fork and spoon to save on weight and space. A favorite of many hikers! The titanium sporkstend to be more resistant and last longer than the plastic ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-Mint Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-mint-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-mint-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls will remind you of the mint flavored chocolates often available on winter Holidays. Chia seeds bring a nice texture and an interesting amount of healthy fats (omega-3) while oats contribute to the consistence and will provide you with long-lasting energy.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) chopped dates ⅓ cup (80 ml) water ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Fruit Leather</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-fruit-leather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-fruit-leather/</guid>
      <description>These pumpkin fruit leathers are perfect snacks to fuel your high intensity autumn adventures. They are also a great way of using pumpkin puree leftovers.
Ingredients  3 apples, peeled, cored and cut in slices 1 (250 ml) pumpkin purée (in can or fresh) 1 tsp. (5 ml) lemon juice ½ tsp. (2.5 ml) pumpkin spices 1 tbsp. (15 ml) maple syrup  Preparation  In a pot, cook the apples in a little water until they are soft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavors, this autumnal curry will satisfy hungry backpackers with 28.2 g of protein per servings! Pretty good for a vegan dish!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) curry powder 2 tsp (10 ml) pumpkin spices ½ tsp (2 ml) fennel seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) vegetable broth powder 1 tbsp (15 ml) pumpkin powder ½ cup (120 ml) red lentils (also called &amp;ldquo;coral&amp;rdquo; lentils) ⅓ cup (80 ml) long grain rice 1 package (5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Pancakes</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Treat yourself on lazy automn backcountry mornings with these delicious sweet pumpkin pancakes!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) all-purpose flour ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp. (30 ml) pumpkin powder 1 tsp. (5 ml) pumpkin spices 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder 2 tsp. (10 ml) granulated sugar 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Pumpkin Powder?</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/pumpkin-powder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/pumpkin-powder/</guid>
      <description>It is pumpkin season, and you find yourself submerged with pumpkins? Why not transform it in pumpkin powder? You’ll be able to preserve it for a long time and use it to make delicious backpacking meals. And you don’t even need a dehydrator to do so! It does require some preparation, but it is so worth it!
Here is how you make pumpkin powder:  If you have fresh pumpkin*, peel it and cut it into cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camp Cuisine Classic Hummus</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/camp-cuisine-hummus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/camp-cuisine-hummus/</guid>
      <description>Note: This menu contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
Taste 3 / 5 Bland when eaten on its own. Add sundried tomatoes, olives, dried herbs or spices to add flavor.
Nutrition analysis 4.5 / 5 Pros: Relatively simple list of ingredients. Half of a package provides 8g of fiber and 16g of protein, which makes a good foundation for a satisfying meal on the trail.
Cons: With 100 mg of sodium by 2 tbsp of prepared hummus, the amount of sodium can easily reach high levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Pearl Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/tropical_pearl_couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/tropical_pearl_couscous/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) Pearl Couscous(also called &amp;ldquo;Israeli Couscous&amp;rdquo;) ⅓ cup (80 ml) dried tropical fruits * ⅓ cup (80 ml) whole milk powder ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese 1 tbsp (15 ml) sweetened coconut flakes  *I used a mix of pineapples and mangoes
Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Chicken Chowder</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</guid>
      <description>This chowder with southwest notes makes a consistent meal with 40g of protein per serving. Perfect to warm up on chilly evenings.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried corn 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 1 tbsp (15 ml) chicken broth powder ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ¼ tsp (1 ml) drief thyme ¼ tsp (1 ml) black pepper 2 tbsp (30 ml) ghee ¾ cup (175 ml) whole milk powder 2 ½ tbsp (37 ml) cornstarch  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Strawberry Extra-Protein Pancakes</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/banana-straw-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/banana-straw-pancake/</guid>
      <description>These pancakes contain 5g of protein more than our other pancake recipe, thanks to the generous amounts of whole milk powder and dehydrated eggs.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) all-purpose flour ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried strawberries and bananas 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trail Cranberry Orange Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/trail-cranberry-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/trail-cranberry-muffins/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever considered baking on the trail? It is totally possible, given you have some time available and you don&amp;rsquo;t mind carrying more fuel for your stove. But if you have cravings for baked goods while on the trail, it is totally worth it!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) all-purpose flour ¼ cup (60 ml) quick oats ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miso and Edamame Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup makes a perfect appetizer and kick-starts the rehydration process after a long day on the trail.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 individual packs of instant miso soup 60 g (2 oz) rice noodles 1 package (20g) freeze dried edamame  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1 liter (4 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s Jambalaya</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</guid>
      <description>If you like spicy food, this recipe will become a backpacking favorite. Packed with proteins, this recipe brings good satiety for a relatively low calorie count. Long distance backpackers, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare both servings for yourself! And if you have some leftovers of chorizo, it makes a great addition to your lunch the following day.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Breakfast Casserole</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</guid>
      <description>This recipe combines savory and sweet tastes for a perfect breakfast. With 25g of proteins, it is a satisfying breakfast.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp (30 ml) 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dried sweet potato dices 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) ¼ tsp (1 ml) of each: dried rosemary and salt ½ tsp (2 ml) paprika 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt ¾ tsp (3 ml) chili powder  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 8 cups (2 liters) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight Rosé Sauce Tortellinis</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried tomato powder* ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried spinach ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil  *You can also use some tomato paste in tube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bear safety: How A Bear Played with My Food</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/bear-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/bear-safety/</guid>
      <description>Yeap, a bear played with my food. Here is what happened. Last weekend, I went on an overnight backpacking trip with my husband and friends in the North Cascades, WA, USA (Goat Lake trail for locals). Before settling in our tents for the night, we stored our food in a bear canister and left it close to where we cooked and far from our tents. A bear found the bear canister (can’t blame him, Gourmet Hiking food is delicious!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morrocan Apricot Chickpeas</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</guid>
      <description>Warm, comforting and sweet, this dish will transport your taste buds somewhere else. Perfect to add variety to your backpacking meals. And you will not believe that this vegan recipe contains 28g of proteins and 6.1 mg of iron (thanks to the dried apricots for this nice contribution!)
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry couscous salt and pepper, to taste 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ cup (60 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated apricots, chopped in small cubes ½ tsp (2 ml) ground coriander seeds ½ tsp (2 ml) ground ginger ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin ¼ tsp (1 ml) cinnamon ¼ tsp (1 ml) paprika ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt 1 pinch of cayenne pepper ⅓ cup (80 ml) roasted almonds  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Curry Rice Vermicelli</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</guid>
      <description>This one-pot recipe is rich in flavors and in carbohydrates! It will provide the energy needed to recharge the batteries in prevision for a long day of backpacking.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 oz (90g) thin rice vermicelli ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried mixed vegetables ¼ cup (60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Extra-Chocolate Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Extra chocolate (cocoa + white chocolate chips) makes this oatmeal deliciously rich and creamy. Treat yourself with this filling and satisfying breakfast to start a long day in the outdoors.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried strawberries 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gourmet Menu for a 5-day Backpacking Trip </title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/5-day-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/5-day-menu/</guid>
      <description>Need food inspiration for a multi-day backpacking trip for this summer? Don’t look further! This 5-day menu will satisfy your taste buds while fueling your muscles for the all those hills to climb. None of these recipes requires the use of a dehydrator. You will only need to combine dry ingredients. Disclaimer: An effort was made to select recipes that are not too heavy, however ultralight backpackers might have to make modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley and Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</guid>
      <description>This super-easy-to-make soup is the perfect way to rehydrate after a long day in the outdoors. It does not contain enough energy (only 112 calories) for a dinner but is the perfect appetizer!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp. (30 ml) 10 minute barley 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried parsley 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms 1&amp;frasl;2 cube of beef broth (for the equivalent of 1 cup of broth)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berries and Granola on-the-go</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</guid>
      <description>The freeze-dried berries bring a nice freshness to this quick breakfast recipe. High in protein (21g/serving) and ridiculously easy to make on the trail, this breakfast will allow you an early start on the trail. Substitute the skim milk powder by full-fat milk powder (e.g. Nido) to add 80 calories to your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) homemade chocolate granola 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight High-Calorie Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</guid>
      <description>The perfect comfort food, this mac&amp;amp;cheese is creamy, rich and made with real (freeze dried) cheddar cheese. When calorie needs are high and space limited in your packs, don&amp;rsquo;t look further!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) macaroni ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried chives ¼ cup (60 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Cranberry Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</guid>
      <description>Couscous for breakfast? Why not! With orange zest and orange flavored cranberry, it is literally a feast! It is as easy as oatmeal to prepare and it makes a nice change.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) medium couscous 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) orange flavored dried cranberries 4 tbsp. (60 ml) sliced roasted almonds 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 8 Tips for Backpacking Meals on a Budget</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/backpacking-on-a-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/backpacking-on-a-budget/</guid>
      <description>You want to get into backpacking but the price of the packaged freeze-dried meals dishearten you? Or you’ve been fueling on ramen for years and just can’t stomach it anymore? Don’t compromise on taste and prepare tasty and cheap backpacking meals. Follow these tips to save big $.
Note: This blog post contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
#1 Cook your own meals rather than relying on commercial freeze-dried meals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garam Masala Chickpea Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>You will start to enjoy this dish before even eating it. Just the smell that comes from the pot while cooking is enough to boost your appetite! Make it vegan by using a vegetable broth instead or add calories by incorporating canola oil.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 tbsp (45 ml) basmati rice 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ tsp (1 ml) coriander seeds, grounded 1½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thru-hikers and Backpackers, Get Your Proteins Right</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/protein-backpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/protein-backpacking/</guid>
      <description>Have you carefully planned your protein intake for your upcoming long backpacking trip or thru-hike? Maybe not… Well, here are four reasons why you should. Then learn what your protein needs are.
Note: This blog post contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
4 reasons why you should pay attention to proteins Proteins are not just for weightlifters Muscles adapt to the training you are doing. When you accumulate the miles, your body wants to increase its capacity to produce energy from nutrients and oxygen so that hiking at a given pace becomes easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry and Vanilla Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Dessert is always good and even more on the trail. Add 10g of protein to your meal by adding this delicious dessert. Top this pudding with fresh blueberries found on the side of the trail, when in season, for extra nutrients and antioxidants. Replace powdered skim milk instead by full-fat milk for extra calories.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) dried blueberries 1 large graham cookie, crushed 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry and Cocoa Nibs Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Cocoa nibs provide a nice crunch to this oatmeal as well as balancing perfectly the sweetness of raspberries. This oatmeal will sustain you for hours with 28g of protein and 15g of fiber per serving.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu for the Hut Visitor</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/hut-visitor-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/hut-visitor-menu/</guid>
      <description>Whether the hut visitor is on skis or snowboard, he enjoyed planning his day in the outdoors based on the warm hut locations. Stopping for lunch at one hut is a must-do and part of the fun of the day. Exercise intensity to get to the shelter and back can vary significantly based on the terrain and who hut visitor companions are.
Nutrition Concern #1: Since getting to the shelter is the goal of this day trip, the hut visitor can decide to delay food or liquid intake until reaching this hut, which can lead to decreased levels of energy and dehydration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Backcountry Recipes with Maple Syrup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/maple-syrup-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/maple-syrup-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
Maple syrup can be use in much more recipes than only pancakes. High in simple sugars, it is a quick source of energy for all your outdoor adventures. Since March is the prime season for maple syrup production, I thought I would share my favorite ways to enjoy maple syrup on the trail.

Get the real thing First of all, you will need real maple syrup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Maple Energetic Gummies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-gummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-gummies/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect snack for high intensity workouts. Going for a stairs training, an interval running session or a high-intensity ski outing? These gummies will provide quick energy as well as electrolytes to help you retain the fluids you are drinking. Can also rescue a training session or an outdoor exploration when the fuel tank gets low, you hit the wall or you bonk (whatever expression you use to describe this state of very low energy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu for the Young Explorers</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/young-explorer-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/young-explorer-menu/</guid>
      <description>The young explorers are happy (or sometimes not that happy) to follow their parents in the outdoors. Depending on the personality and the energy level of the young explorer, the moving pace can be pretty high or painfully slow. But what should we feed these young explorers?
Nutrition Concern #1: Young explorers can be very attuned to his/her hunger cues or too excited to be in the outdoors and forget about eating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 tips for the perfect foodie Valentine’s Day in the Backcountry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/valentine-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/valentine-day/</guid>
      <description>This year for Valentine’s Day, why not doing something different? Your partner or spouse prefers the quietness of nature to the crowded environment of restaurants? And thinks there is nothing like spending time together hiking, snowshoeing or skiing? Instead of going to a restaurant with your lover (and some many other couples!), why not packing lovely food and enjoy it in the outdoors? Check out these five pieces of advice for a successful outdoor Valentine’s Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expedition Molasse Cookies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/expedition-molasse-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/expedition-molasse-cookies/</guid>
      <description>These heavy-duty cookies are perfect to fuel your next expedition. They contain healthy fats (from cashew butter and chia seeds) and almost 10g of protein, which is huge for a cookie! However, these nutrition components do not undermine the taste. With a strong molasse taste and a smooth texture, these cookies will remind you ok sweet childhood memories!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) winter squash (e.g. butternut) or sweet potato puree ⅔ cup (160 ml) molasse ¾ cup (180 ml) cashew butter 2 eggs 1 tsp (5 ml) vanilla extract ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu for the Birdwatcher</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/birdwatcher-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/birdwatcher-menu/</guid>
      <description>The birdwatcher prefers to describe his/her day by the number of birds or animals observed rather than the km covered. The breaks are frequent (this is how you spot birds right?), so are the opportunities to eat. The exercise intensity is usually low to moderate and given the relatively easy pace, extra weight in the backpack is not a major issue.
Nutrition Concern: Given the relatively low exercise intensity, the energy needs are relatively modest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu for the Intense Backcountry Skier</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/backcountry-ski-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/backcountry-ski-menu/</guid>
      <description>The intense backcountry skier skins up as quickly as possible in the early morning to have fresh tracks and repeats this as often as possible well into the afternoon (or until the avalanche risk becomes too high). Usually, he exercises at high intensity, which increases the energy (calorie) needs and water loss through sweating and heavy breathing. On the other hand, breaks are short, if existent, and space in day pack limited since it is almost full of all the avalanche gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macadamia nuts, raspberries and white chocolate goodness</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/macadamia-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/macadamia-bar/</guid>
      <description>These bars will fuel your winter adventures and put a smile on your face after each bite! They stay soft even at freezing temperature, which make them easy to eat during a snowy day. Ok, they are a bit high in fat for a high intensity training but are perfect for these long outings on snowshoes or on backcountry skis.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) pitted dates, cut in small pieces 2 tbsp (30 ml) water 1 ½ cup (375 ml) frozen raspberries, divided 1 tsp (5 ml) vanilla extract 1 tsp (5 ml) baking powder 2 cups (500 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) whole wheat flour ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder ¼ cup (60 ml) sweetened shredded coconut ½ cup (125 ml) macadamia nuts 1 pinch of salt ⅔ cup (160 ml) white chocolate chips 1 tbsp (15 ml) unsalted butter  Preparation  Combine the dates, water and 1 cup (250 ml) of frozen raspberries in a small pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple candied pecans and apples with sea salt sprinkles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</guid>
      <description>The fanciest of trail mixes, this mix combines sweet and salty flavors for a premium snack on the trail. It is a good option for these cold outdoor adventures when maximizing the energy density (calories/weight) is a must. It also does taste super good on day snowshoeing or backcountry skiing adventures! Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) gluten-free puffed rice 1 cup (250 ml) pecans ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ¼ cup (60 ml) real maple syrup ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Hot Drinks to Fuel Your Winter Adventures</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/hot-drinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/hot-drinks/</guid>
      <description>There is nothing more satisfying on a winter adventure than sipping on a hot drink while looking at an amazing snow-covered view. What about making this moment even more satisfying by bringing tasteful drinks on your adventures. Check these 10 delicious hot drinks ideas!
For sweet tooths Sweetened creamy earl grey tea Pick your favorite Earl Grey tea, add it with hot water in a thermos. Then, for extra energy out there, add milk (or cream -yum!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Cheese and Ham Bread</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cheese-ham-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cheese-ham-bread/</guid>
      <description>A slice of bread that contains 18g of proteins? Yeap, and it tastes delicious! This bread is moist but dense enough to travel well in a backpack. For those who worry that making bread is complicated, this recipe will prove you the contrary! The fat from the cheese keeps this bread moist for 4 to 5 days if well wrapped.
Ingredients  8.8 oz (250 g) black forest ham, cut in small cubes 1 tbsp (15 ml) olive oil 3½ cup (875 ml) all-purpose flour ¾ tsp (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s French Toasts</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Perfect for these laid-back mornings when watching the sunrise while sipping your coffee and enjoying a delicious breakfast is more important than hitting the trail early! Feel free to add your personal twist by changing the toppings: walnuts + honey or cranberries + white chocolate + macademia nuts. Just make sure to include nuts or seeds to bump the energy (calorie) content of your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Foods to Keep Warm in the Backcountry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/foods-keep-warm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/foods-keep-warm/</guid>
      <description>Reaching a mountaintop still covered with snow in August, exploring glaciers at night or shredding fresh powder on your backcountry skis: extraordinary outdoor adventures can also mean incredibly cold temperatures. How can your food choices help you to keep warm out there? Here are the top 5 foods to keep warm in the backcountry:
Soups A great way to warm up and rehydrate after a long day in the backcountry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tons of ideas to pimp your pasta meals on the trail</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/pasta-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 08:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/pasta-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Pasta and other wheat products have a kind of a bad reputation these days. This is too bad because pasta is rich in carbohydrates, the preferred energy source of muscles while hiking and performing other physical activity tasks. Pasta made with wheat also contain several B vitamins. For a high fiber content, go for the whole wheat or whole grain pasta.
Versatile, pasta is an easy go-to option for many campers and backpackers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and Pecan Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-pecan-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-pecan-muffins/</guid>
      <description>If you went apple picking and you want to use these apples to fuel your next outdoor adventure, this recipe is for you! These muffins are dense enough to keep their shape if stored at the bottom of your backpack but still very moist.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) brown sugar 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oatmeal 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Mushroom Egg Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</guid>
      <description>Perfect recipe for mushroom lovers! Rich and creamy, this dish is the perfect comfort food on a chilly backpacking night. Technically, this recipe is not vegetarian because of the beef broth added to it but it can easily be changed for a vegetable broth.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 ½ cups (875 ml) dry egg noodles ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) dried chanterelle mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) 1 cube beef broth 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried tarragon 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried chives Black pepper to taste 1 can (225 ml) Table Cream by Nestlé(thick cream)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Dried Tomato and Basil Pesto Tortellini</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) ½ cup (125 ml) sun dried tomatoes ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) basil pesto, in a tube ¼ cup ( 60 ml) pine nuts, roasted  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu for a 3-day backpacking trip with ingredients available at your local grocery store</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/3-day-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/3-day-menu/</guid>
      <description>No time to dehydrate all of your food before your next backpacking trip? No need to order online a bunch of different (and expensive) freeze-dried foods! It can be easy to make tasty and nutritious meals from ingredients available at your grocery store. Here is an example:
Day 1 Breakfast:  Cranberry, Orange, Dark Chocolate and Sweet potato muffins Muffins Coffee latte and a piece of fruit to eat in the car while driving to the trailhead  Lunch:  Your favorite turkey and swiss cheese sandwich prepared at home  Dinner:  Smoked salmon Pasta, chocolate covered almonds</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are your fluid needs at high altitudes?</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/altitude-fluid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/altitude-fluid/</guid>
      <description>Hiking and backpacking in remote (and awesome) places such as mountains and glaciers often means reaching higher altitudes than where we normally live. The higher we climb the more the effects of altitude will be felt, such as increased perception of effort (it becomes more difficult to perform the same task) and increased ventilation (breathing more heavily). Some effects of altitude are less noticeable, yet just as significant, such as changes in fluid needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and Peppers Egg Scramble with Hashbrowns</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is very filling with a surprising 26g of protein per serving. It is also delicious and a nice change from the sweet breakfast options.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried chives 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</guid>
      <description>These energy balls have a subtil coffee taste that will please the coffee lovers but are sweet enough to please the non coffee drinkers. This snack kept me going on a recent climb of Mt.Rainier that was longer than expected. I am not sure how I managed to save one energy ball to take a picture at the top&amp;hellip;
Ingredients  ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 1 ½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Alfredo Gnocchi</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavor (and in calories!), this recipe is perfect for these difficult overnight backpacking trips.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 package of 17.6 oz (500g) gnocchi 3.25 oz. (92g) pre-cooked bacon 1 can 7.6 fl. oz. (225 ml) table cream (I used Table Cream by Nestlé) 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried chives 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried parsley ⅓ cup (80 ml) parmigiano reggiano, shredded ¼ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pancake</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Pancakes are delicious at home and even better on the trail. Topped with real maple syrup and it is pretty close to perfection. Add a fresh coffee and you are in breakfast paradise!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅔ cup (150 ml) all-purpose flour 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 4 tbsp. (60 ml) real maple syrup 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unique Menus for Overnight Backpacking Trips</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/overnight-menus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/overnight-menus/</guid>
      <description>Overnight trips are perfect for backpacking novices and for experienced (and busy) outdoor adventurers. Here are 3 menus to help you plan your next overnight trip.
Let’s consider that the breakfast of day 1 and dinner of day 2 are eaten at home or on the road.
Menu 1: The Meat Lover Day 1 Lunch  Your favorite roast beef sandwich prepared at home Apple  Day 1 Dinner  Oregano, Tomato and Sausage Orzo Homemade Hot Chocolate  Day 2 Breakfast  Egg, Bacon and Hashbrown Skillet  Day 2 Lunch  Beef Jerky Cheese stick Crackers Dried fruits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregano, Tomato and Sausage Orzo</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is perfect for overnight backpacking trips or when weight and space in your backpacks are not issues.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) olive oil 2 packages of cooked chicken sausages (12 oz or 340g each)* 2 cups (500 ml) dry orzo ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used a mix) 1 tsp. (10 ml) dried oregano leaves 4.5 oz (127 g) double-concentrated tomato paste.  *If you are worried about food safety, you can freeze the sausages prior to your trip and pack them frozen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate and Raspberries Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 2 Oreo cookies, crushed 3 tbsp. (45 ml) instant chocolate pudding mix 3 tbsp. (45 ml) powdered skim milk  Equipment  Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the bag, no judgement here!) Spork or spoon  Before trip  Mix in plastic bag #1: raspberries and Oreo cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-banana oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This delicious and somewhat special oatmeal (chocolate for breakfast!) is filling with 18g of protein and 9g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1½ cup (375 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) coconut milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) cocoa powder ½ cup (125 ml) banana chips ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting findings at Trader Joe’s</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/trader-joes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/trader-joes/</guid>
      <description>Trader Joe’s grocery store, with its unique products, can be a great source of inspiration for new backpacking recipes. Here are some of recent findings:
Freeze dried fruits Freeze dried foods have a lot of advantages compared to dehydrated: -They tend to have a flavor more similar to fresh foods -They contain more nutrients, thanks to the faster transformation process -They rehydrate faster. However, freeze dried foods can be expensive. Not at Trader Joe’s!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Salmon Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 ½ cups (625 ml) dry pasta (I used penne) ½ cup (125 ml) dried bell peppers 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried chives ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ½ cup (125 ml) powdered milk 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried dill Black pepper to taste 1 Alfredo sauce package(I used the brand Knorr) 2 packages of smoked salmon jerky(2 x 3oz)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hot Chocolate</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>Warm, sweet and rich, this basic hot chocolate recipe will help you to relax after a long day of adventuring. This drink contains 12g of high-quality protein, which is 11g more than your commercial hot chocolate powder prepared with hot water! It also provides some quickly absorbed carbohydrates and liquids to kickstart the recovery process.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) sugar 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa 4 tbsp. (60 ml) powdered milk pinch of salt  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Cup to drink Sporks or forks  Before trip  Mix all the ingredients together  At camp  Bring to boil about 1 cup (250 ml) of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange and Chocolate Protein Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choco-protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choco-protein/</guid>
      <description>Some Canadian friends told me these protein balls remind them of the famous Tim Hortons’ Timbits. Although these protein balls have similar taste and shape than the Timbits, their nutritional value is way more interesting with 4.7g of fiber and 9.3 g of protein per serving (2 balls).
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) orange juice 2 tsp (10 ml) fresh orange zest 3 tbsp (45 ml) cocoa 1 cup (250 ml) quick oats ¾ cup (175 ml) whey protein isolate ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut flour, divided  Preparation  Bring dates and orange juice to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping for Backpacking Trips at Whole Foods</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/shopping-for-backpacking-at-whole-foods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/shopping-for-backpacking-at-whole-foods/</guid>
      <description>Who said you couldn&amp;rsquo;t shop for your next backpacking trip at the same store you shop for your groceries? Ok, Whole Foods is not known for low prices… but there are still some interesting deals to make there! Check out these ideas of foods to put in your shopping cart for your next backpacking trip!
Wide variety of dried fruits We all know that dried fruit are great snacks on the trail, providing carbohydrates to keep your energy level high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Egg and Hashbrowns Skillet</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</guid>
      <description>If you like bacon, you’ll love this recipe! It is filling, with 18g of protein per serving, it is a good way to start a day in the outdoors!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried chives ⅓ cup (80 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 3 tbsp. (45 ml) canola oil 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need your espresso fix even on the trail?</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/caffeine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 16:50:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/caffeine/</guid>
      <description>Your need for an espresso fix has nothing to do with how coffee tastes (Ok, the taste can be pretty wonderful!), but rather with the drug that it contains: caffeine. Let’s face it: most of us are caffeine addicts. But how does this drug affect us? Can it provide any benefits to hikers and backpackers?
What is it? Caffeine is a chemical naturally found in plants such as coffee beans, cocoa beans, kola nuts, tea leaves and guarana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krave Chili Lime Beef Jerky</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/krave-beef-jerky-chili-lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/krave-beef-jerky-chili-lime/</guid>
      <description>Taste 3 / 5 Subtle notes of lime for the first bite but for the following bites, it seems like the spicyness is the only thing noticeable. Texture is ok.
Nutrition analysis 3.5 / 5 Pros: Low in fat (1.5g/oz). Sodium (380mg/oz) is lower than in other jerkys. Ingredient list relatively easy to understand.
Cons: more carbohydrates than protein in a meat-based product!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping for Backpacking Food at the Grocery Store</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/shopping-for-backpacking-food-at-the-grocery-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/shopping-for-backpacking-food-at-the-grocery-store/</guid>
      <description>No time to shop online for specialized freeze-dried or dehydrated foods? Your regular grocery store has a lot more to offer for backpacking foods than you might think!
Be creative A lot of the foods in grocery stores can be used for backpacking trips. Here are some examples:
 Category Examples   Grains Pasta, rice, couscous, rice noodles   Seasonings Dried spices and herbs, small containers of curry paste or tomato pasta, parmesan cheese   Vegetables Sun-dried tomatoes, dehydrated onions or chives (in the spices sections), dehydrated mushrooms   Breakfast Instant oatmeal, wheat cream, granola, breakfast cereals, milk powder    Snacks Bars, dried fruits, nuts, seeds, premixed trail mix    Protein options can be challenging Since most protein sources are either refrigerated, frozen or in can, finding lightweight and shelf-stable protein options can be tricky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunt&#39;s Tomato Paste</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/hunts-tomato-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/hunts-tomato-paste/</guid>
      <description>Taste 5 / 5 Tomato pasta in purée. No added herbs or seasoning. It is very versatile and can be used in a lot of recipes on the trail: pasta sauce, mexican rice, chili, stews and soups.
Nutrition analysis 4.5 / 5 Pros: Low in sodium (25mg/ pouch) and high in potassium (420 mg/pouch). It looks like there is no added sugar (according to the ingredient list). High fiber content (3g/pouch).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Valuable Resource for Outdoor Enthusiasts!</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/website-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/blog-post/website-launch/</guid>
      <description>When I moved from the East coast of Canada (Québec) to the West Coast of USA, I discovered a world of opportunities in terms of hiking, backpacking, rock climbing and backcountry skiing! As a registered dietitian, I was excited to get into food planning for my trips, but when I looked online for resources, it was hard to find recipes I liked and made with easy-to-find ingredients. It is on a backpacking trip in Grand Teton National Park that I had idea of Gourmet Hiking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmega Mint Crisp</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oatmega-mint-crisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oatmega-mint-crisp/</guid>
      <description>Taste 4.5 / 5 Nice texture that stays soft even at freezing temperature. Good taste of chocolate and mint. Hardly noticeable taste of whey
Nutrition analysis 4 / 5 Pros: High content of fiber (7g/bar), low simple sugars (5g/bar) and high content in protein (14g/bar) which helps with satiety. It makes it a good snack for low to moderate intensity activities. Whey comes from grass-fed cows and fish oil from responsibly-caught fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oberto’s Applewood Smoked Bacon Jerky</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oberto-applewood-smoked-bacon-jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oberto-applewood-smoked-bacon-jerky/</guid>
      <description>Taste 4.5 / 5 Authentic taste of bacon with a nice applewood smoke twist to it. Although the jerky is pretty dry, it is not too tough to eat. This jerky is good to eat on its own but could also be a good addition to dishes cooked on the trail such as egg scrambles or alfredo pasta.
Nutrition analysis 2.5 / 5 Pros: High in protein (12g/oz) for a jerky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tillamook Country Smoker Teriyaki Meat Stick</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/tillamook-teriyaki-meat-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/tillamook-teriyaki-meat-stick/</guid>
      <description>Taste 2.5 / 5 Nothing exceptional here. The taste reminded me of hot-dogs… Inside texture is soft, the outside layer being a little rough.
Nutrition analysis 2 / 5 Pros: not much to say here… The first ingredients are beef and pork!
Cons: Long list of ingredients that required advanced nutrition knowledge to understand. High in sodium (533mg/oz). High in fat (8g/oz) and relatively high in saturated fat (3g/oz). Relatively low in protein (5g/oz) for meat-based product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tillamook Smoked &amp; Dried Beef Steak Cuts Teriyaki</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/smoked-dried-beef-steak-cuts-teriyaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/smoked-dried-beef-steak-cuts-teriyaki/</guid>
      <description>Taste 3.5 / 5 The thick pieces change from the usual thin sliced jerky. Texture is soft. Taste does not offer anything out of the ordinary: sweet soy sauce&amp;hellip;
Nutrition analysis 4 / 5 Pros: Ingredients’ list is short and very easy to understand. More protein than carbohydrates, which is what we are looking for in a jerky!
Cons: Sodium (450 mg/oz) is pretty high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**  * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Granola</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</guid>
      <description>Are your breakfasts always the same and boring? Not anymore with this recipe of chocolate granola. Hey yes, a recipe with chocolate created by a dietitian for breakfast! And in extra, this granola is fortified in protein for long lasting satiety.
Each portion of 3&amp;frasl;4 cup contains 9g of protein and is low in fat. Add Greek yogurt or cottage cheese and fruits (I chose frozen raspberry and cherries for this picture) to this granola to make a complete meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa and Peanut Butter Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls were a success on a backcountry ski trip! They are low-fat and are packed with carbohydrates for energy during the long grueling skin up sections.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats ⅓ cup (80 ml) powdered peanut butter 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa  Preparation  Bring dates and water to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 cup roasted hazelnuts ¼ cup cocoa  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Bar</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-bar/</guid>
      <description>Perfect bars to fuel your winter adventures! They stay soft even at freezing temperature, which make them easy to eat during a snowy day. Their subtle coffee aroma along with powerful chocolate flavors will make you wish you brought more of these bars with you! Please note, there is about 20mg of caffeine per bar, which is the equivalent of about ¼ of a cup of brewed coffee.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) pitted dates, cut in small pieces 1 cup (250 ml) water 2 tbsp (30 ml) instant coffee 1 tsp (5 ml) baking powder 1 cup (250 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) whole wheat flour ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder ¼ cup (60 ml) sweetened shredded coconut ⅓ cup (80 ml) cocoa powder 1 pinch of salt ⅔ cup (160 ml) semi-sweet chocolate chips 1 tbsp (15 ml) unsalted butter  Preparation  Combine the dates and water in a small pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange, Dark Chocolate and Sweet Potato Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</guid>
      <description>These delicious muffins are a good option for breakfast-on-the-go when driving to the mountains early in the morning. Bring a fruit and a portion of milk or drinkable yogurt for a more complete breakfast!
Alternatively, these muffins can be a good snack for a low-intensity training.
Ingredients  1 small sweet potato, peeled and cut in medium pieces 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin and Spices Cookies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-spices-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-spices-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Sweet and satisfying, these cookies will be the perfect partners for your next hiking or long bike ride. Rich in carbohydrate, they will provide the fuel you need for your next outdoor adventure. Their protein and fiber content will make you fill full until your next stop.
Vincent and I tested these cookies on a climb of Mt. St. Helens, WA. The cookies were even better on the mountain than in my kitchen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp and Rosé Sauce Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups (500 ml) dry pasta (I used macaroni) 1 can (4 oz – 113g) of shrimp 1 can (6 oz – 170 g) of tomato paste (personally I took one with added herbs for extra flavor!) 3 tbsp (45 ml) powdered milk ½ cup Parmesan cheese 1 tsp (5 ml) dried herbs (I mixed oregano and basil) ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used green peas, corn, tomatoes and spinach)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Can opener Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, not judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini, Lemon and Blueberries Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</guid>
      <description>If you have a garden that produces an impressive quantity of zucchinis and that you don’t know what to do with them at this point, this recipe is for you!
As usual, I tested this recipe in the outdoor. Since it makes a dozen, I brought them on several adventures: from rock climbing to hiking on different trails in Washington State.
Sweet and satisfying these muffins make a good snack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Why Gourmet Hiking? The mission of Gourmet Hiking is to translate nutrition science into tasty recipes and resources for hikers and backpackers to help them enjoy their favorite activity. Science to trail as a basis for everything. All recipes, blog posts and other resources available on Gourmet Hiking are based on sports nutrition and exercise physiology scientific findings. Taste as the main criteria for recipe creation. Nutrient composition of recipes is analyzed but if a recipe doesn’t pass the test of taste buds on the trail, it is not published.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>