<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-posts on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-posts on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Valuable Resource for Outdoor Enthusiasts!</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/website-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/website-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I moved from the East coast of Canada (Québec) to the West Coast of USA, I discovered a world of opportunities in terms of hiking, backpacking, rock climbing and backcountry skiing! As a registered dietitian, I was excited to get into food planning for my trips, but when I looked online for resources, it was hard to find recipes I liked and made with easy-to-find ingredients. It is on a backpacking trip in Grand Teton National Park that I had idea of Gourmet Hiking. Almost 2 years later and after a lot of trial and errors, this is it: Gourmet Hiking is online!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/img/posts/website-launch/logo.jpg&#34; class=&#34;recipe-right&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I am a registered dietitian specialized in sports nutrition and eating disorders with work experience both in research and on-the-field settings, which led me to choose these 2 core principles for Gourmet Hiking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Science to trail as a basis for everything:&lt;/em&gt; Nutrition science has so much to offer to outdoor enthusiasts in terms of physical performance, health and enjoyment improvement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taste as the main criteria for recipe creation:&lt;/em&gt; I believe eating need to be enjoyable and satisfying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I invite you to explore my website to find:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy-to-cook &lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post&#34;&gt;Blog posts&lt;/a&gt; in which I translate the most recent scientific findings in practical tips for your next trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/product-reviews&#34;&gt;Product reviews&lt;/a&gt; to help you select the best hiking food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And much more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let your comments, suggestions for future posts or website improvements tips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Gen Masson, MSc, RD, CD&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>