<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-posts on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-posts on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping for Backpacking Food at the Grocery Store</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/shopping-for-backpacking-food-at-the-grocery-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/shopping-for-backpacking-food-at-the-grocery-store/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;No time to shop online for specialized freeze-dried or dehydrated foods? Your regular grocery store has a lot more to offer for backpacking foods than you might think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-creative&#34;&gt;Be creative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the foods in grocery stores can be used for backpacking trips. Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-bordered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Examples&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Grains&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Pasta, rice, couscous, rice noodles&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Seasonings&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Dried spices and herbs, small containers of curry paste or tomato pasta, parmesan cheese&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Vegetables&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Sun-dried tomatoes, dehydrated onions or chives (in the spices sections), dehydrated mushrooms&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Breakfast&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Instant oatmeal, wheat cream, granola, breakfast cereals, milk powder
&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Snacks&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Bars, dried fruits, nuts, seeds, premixed trail mix
&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/img/posts/grocery_shopping/thumbnail.jpg&#34; class=&#34;recipe-right&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;protein-options-can-be-challenging&#34;&gt;Protein options can be challenging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most protein sources are either refrigerated, frozen or in can, finding lightweight and shelf-stable protein options can be tricky. To add to the complexity, some shelf-stable options involves long preparation time such as dried beans. With some ingenuity, there are ways to get a variety of protein options at low cost:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individually sealed cheese and meat sticks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dry lentils (cook faster than other dry beans)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooked fish or meat in vacuum-sealed pouches (i.e. salmon, tuna, chicken, ham)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milk powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beef and other types of jerkys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shelf-stable smoked salmon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pay-attention-to-the-weight-and-volume-of-packages&#34;&gt;Pay attention to the weight and volume of packages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of shelf stable foods are in cans. This means, carrying the can (and its weight) in and out the trail. Look for plastic packages or other lightweight packages. In the case of dry foods, you can also transfer the food in Ziploc-type plastic bags to save on the volume and weight of packages. For example, you can transfer the content of your favorite mac&amp;amp;cheese box in a plastic bag to save on space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more ideas of backpacking foods in grocery stores near you. I will share my findings I make in different grocery stores from the Pacific Northwest on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Valuable Resource for Outdoor Enthusiasts!</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/website-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post/website-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I moved from the East coast of Canada (Québec) to the West Coast of USA, I discovered a world of opportunities in terms of hiking, backpacking, rock climbing and backcountry skiing! As a registered dietitian, I was excited to get into food planning for my trips, but when I looked online for resources, it was hard to find recipes I liked and made with easy-to-find ingredients. It is on a backpacking trip in Grand Teton National Park that I had idea of Gourmet Hiking. Almost 2 years later and after a lot of trial and errors, this is it: Gourmet Hiking is online!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/img/posts/website-launch/logo.jpg&#34; class=&#34;recipe-right&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I am a registered dietitian specialized in sports nutrition and eating disorders with work experience both in research and on-the-field settings, which led me to choose these 2 core principles for Gourmet Hiking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Science to trail as a basis for everything:&lt;/em&gt; Nutrition science has so much to offer to outdoor enthusiasts in terms of physical performance, health and enjoyment improvement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taste as the main criteria for recipe creation:&lt;/em&gt; I believe eating need to be enjoyable and satisfying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I invite you to explore my website to find:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy-to-cook &lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/blog-post&#34;&gt;Blog posts&lt;/a&gt; in which I translate the most recent scientific findings in practical tips for your next trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gourmethiking.com/product-reviews&#34;&gt;Product reviews&lt;/a&gt; to help you select the best hiking food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And much more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let your comments, suggestions for future posts or website improvements tips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Gen Masson, MSc, RD, CD&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>