<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gluten Free on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/gluten-free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gluten Free on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/gluten-free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Hashbrowns - Just add water</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/breakfast-hashbrown-just-add-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/breakfast-hashbrown-just-add-water/</guid>
      <description>Hashbrowns ready in less time that needed to pack your camp in the morning!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried chives ¼ cup (60 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 4.2 oz. (119g) dehydrated hashbrowns potatoes ½ cup (125 ml) dried bell peppers 1 tbsp dried marjolam  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water 2 1-quart mylar bags 2 clips to hold the mylar bags closed Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Mango Energetic Gummies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mango-gummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mango-gummies/</guid>
      <description>These sweet mango gummies will fuel your high-intensity workouts perfectly. Going for a stairs training, an interval running session or a high-intensity ski outing? These gummies will provide quick energy as well as electrolytes to help you retain the fluids you are drinking. Can also rescue a training session or an outdoor exploration when the fuel tank gets low, you hit the wall or you bonk (whatever expression you use to describe this state of very low energy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Curried Chickpeas</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/roasted-curried-chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/roasted-curried-chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>Crispy and salty, these roasted chickpeas are healthy alternatives to chips with their high content in fiber. Due to their relatively low energy density, this snack would be better for day trips or shorter backpacking trips, when energy needs are more modest and space is not an issue.
Ingredients  1 can (18 oz or 540 ml) chickpeas, rinsed 1½ tbsp (22 ml) olive oil 1 tbsp (15 ml) curry powder 1 generous pinch of salt  Preparation  Pat dry the chickpeas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Peppercorn and Orange Candied Pecans</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pink-peppercorn-orange-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pink-peppercorn-orange-pecans/</guid>
      <description>This spicy and sweet seasoning is so addictive! If you are able to refain from eating them all before heading to the outdoors, this snack made of nuts will provide energy during long low-intensity outdoor activities. They also make great gifts!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pecans (whole or halves) 1½ cup (22.5 ml) honey 1 tbsp (15 ml) pink peppercorns, slightly crushed 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-Mint Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-mint-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-mint-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls will remind you of the mint flavored chocolates often available on winter Holidays. Chia seeds bring a nice texture and an interesting amount of healthy fats (omega-3) while oats contribute to the consistence and will provide you with long-lasting energy.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) chopped dates ⅓ cup (80 ml) water ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Fruit Leather</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-fruit-leather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-fruit-leather/</guid>
      <description>These pumpkin fruit leathers are perfect snacks to fuel your high intensity autumn adventures. They are also a great way of using pumpkin puree leftovers.
Ingredients  3 apples, peeled, cored and cut in slices 1 (250 ml) pumpkin purée (in can or fresh) 1 tsp. (5 ml) lemon juice ½ tsp. (2.5 ml) pumpkin spices 1 tbsp. (15 ml) maple syrup  Preparation  In a pot, cook the apples in a little water until they are soft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavors, this autumnal curry will satisfy hungry backpackers with 28.2 g of protein per servings! Pretty good for a vegan dish!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) curry powder 2 tsp (10 ml) pumpkin spices ½ tsp (2 ml) fennel seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) vegetable broth powder 1 tbsp (15 ml) pumpkin powder ½ cup (120 ml) red lentils (also called &amp;ldquo;coral&amp;rdquo; lentils) ⅓ cup (80 ml) long grain rice 1 package (5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Chicken Chowder</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</guid>
      <description>This chowder with southwest notes makes a consistent meal with 40g of protein per serving. Perfect to warm up on chilly evenings.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried corn 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 1 tbsp (15 ml) chicken broth powder ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ¼ tsp (1 ml) drief thyme ¼ tsp (1 ml) black pepper 2 tbsp (30 ml) ghee ¾ cup (175 ml) whole milk powder 2 ½ tbsp (37 ml) cornstarch  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miso and Edamame Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup makes a perfect appetizer and kick-starts the rehydration process after a long day on the trail.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 individual packs of instant miso soup 60 g (2 oz) rice noodles 1 package (20g) freeze dried edamame  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1 liter (4 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s Jambalaya</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</guid>
      <description>If you like spicy food, this recipe will become a backpacking favorite. Packed with proteins, this recipe brings good satiety for a relatively low calorie count. Long distance backpackers, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare both servings for yourself! And if you have some leftovers of chorizo, it makes a great addition to your lunch the following day.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Breakfast Casserole</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</guid>
      <description>This recipe combines savory and sweet tastes for a perfect breakfast. With 25g of proteins, it is a satisfying breakfast.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp (30 ml) 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dried sweet potato dices 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) ¼ tsp (1 ml) of each: dried rosemary and salt ½ tsp (2 ml) paprika 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt ¾ tsp (3 ml) chili powder  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 8 cups (2 liters) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Extra-Chocolate Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Extra chocolate (cocoa + white chocolate chips) makes this oatmeal deliciously rich and creamy. Treat yourself with this filling and satisfying breakfast to start a long day in the outdoors.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried strawberries 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Cranberry Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</guid>
      <description>Couscous for breakfast? Why not! With orange zest and orange flavored cranberry, it is literally a feast! It is as easy as oatmeal to prepare and it makes a nice change.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) medium couscous 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) orange flavored dried cranberries 4 tbsp. (60 ml) sliced roasted almonds 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garam Masala Chickpea Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>You will start to enjoy this dish before even eating it. Just the smell that comes from the pot while cooking is enough to boost your appetite! Make it vegan by using a vegetable broth instead or add calories by incorporating canola oil.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 tbsp (45 ml) basmati rice 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ tsp (1 ml) coriander seeds, grounded 1½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry and Cocoa Nibs Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Cocoa nibs provide a nice crunch to this oatmeal as well as balancing perfectly the sweetness of raspberries. This oatmeal will sustain you for hours with 28g of protein and 15g of fiber per serving.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Maple Energetic Gummies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-gummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-gummies/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect snack for high intensity workouts. Going for a stairs training, an interval running session or a high-intensity ski outing? These gummies will provide quick energy as well as electrolytes to help you retain the fluids you are drinking. Can also rescue a training session or an outdoor exploration when the fuel tank gets low, you hit the wall or you bonk (whatever expression you use to describe this state of very low energy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expedition Molasse Cookies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/expedition-molasse-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/expedition-molasse-cookies/</guid>
      <description>These heavy-duty cookies are perfect to fuel your next expedition. They contain healthy fats (from cashew butter and chia seeds) and almost 10g of protein, which is huge for a cookie! However, these nutrition components do not undermine the taste. With a strong molasse taste and a smooth texture, these cookies will remind you ok sweet childhood memories!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) winter squash (e.g. butternut) or sweet potato puree ⅔ cup (160 ml) molasse ¾ cup (180 ml) cashew butter 2 eggs 1 tsp (5 ml) vanilla extract ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple candied pecans and apples with sea salt sprinkles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</guid>
      <description>The fanciest of trail mixes, this mix combines sweet and salty flavors for a premium snack on the trail. It is a good option for these cold outdoor adventures when maximizing the energy density (calories/weight) is a must. It also does taste super good on day snowshoeing or backcountry skiing adventures! Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) gluten-free puffed rice 1 cup (250 ml) pecans ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ¼ cup (60 ml) real maple syrup ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and Peppers Egg Scramble with Hashbrowns</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is very filling with a surprising 26g of protein per serving. It is also delicious and a nice change from the sweet breakfast options.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried chives 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</guid>
      <description>These energy balls have a subtil coffee taste that will please the coffee lovers but are sweet enough to please the non coffee drinkers. This snack kept me going on a recent climb of Mt.Rainier that was longer than expected. I am not sure how I managed to save one energy ball to take a picture at the top&amp;hellip;
Ingredients  ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 1 ½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-banana oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This delicious and somewhat special oatmeal (chocolate for breakfast!) is filling with 18g of protein and 9g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1½ cup (375 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) coconut milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) cocoa powder ½ cup (125 ml) banana chips ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange and Chocolate Protein Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choco-protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choco-protein/</guid>
      <description>Some Canadian friends told me these protein balls remind them of the famous Tim Hortons’ Timbits. Although these protein balls have similar taste and shape than the Timbits, their nutritional value is way more interesting with 4.7g of fiber and 9.3 g of protein per serving (2 balls).
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) orange juice 2 tsp (10 ml) fresh orange zest 3 tbsp (45 ml) cocoa 1 cup (250 ml) quick oats ¾ cup (175 ml) whey protein isolate ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut flour, divided  Preparation  Bring dates and orange juice to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Egg and Hashbrowns Skillet</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</guid>
      <description>If you like bacon, you’ll love this recipe! It is filling, with 18g of protein per serving, it is a good way to start a day in the outdoors!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried chives ⅓ cup (80 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 3 tbsp. (45 ml) canola oil 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**  * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Granola</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</guid>
      <description>Are your breakfasts always the same and boring? Not anymore with this recipe of chocolate granola. Hey yes, a recipe with chocolate created by a dietitian for breakfast! And in extra, this granola is fortified in protein for long lasting satiety.
Each portion of 3&amp;frasl;4 cup contains 9g of protein and is low in fat. Add Greek yogurt or cottage cheese and fruits (I chose frozen raspberry and cherries for this picture) to this granola to make a complete meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa and Peanut Butter Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls were a success on a backcountry ski trip! They are low-fat and are packed with carbohydrates for energy during the long grueling skin up sections.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats ⅓ cup (80 ml) powdered peanut butter 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa  Preparation  Bring dates and water to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 cup roasted hazelnuts ¼ cup cocoa  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>