<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breakfast on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/breakfast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breakfast on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/breakfast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mango-rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mango-rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Rice for breakfast? Why not? This creamy and slightly sweetened rice pudding recipe is perfect for cold mornings in the backcountry. Complete this breakfast with a homemade hot chocolate or latte to boost the protein and calorie count.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) basmati or other long grain rice ½ cup (125 ml) unsweetened dried mangoes* 1 tbsp (15 ml) white sugar* 1 pinch of salt ⅔ cup (160 ml) skim milk powder 2 tbsp (30 ml) coconut milk powder 2 tbsp (30 ml) unsweetened coconut chips  *If using dried mangoes with added sugar, skip the white sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berry Choco Overnight Oats</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berry-choco-overnight-oats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berry-choco-overnight-oats/</guid>
      <description>This overnight oat recipe is perfect to kick-start a long day of outdoor adventures, without having to use a stove. Just pour water over the oats mix the night before and let time makes its effect. Customize your overnight oats by switching up the dried fruits, nuts and flavors.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Chocolate Breakfast Quinoa</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-quinoa/</guid>
      <description>Quinoa for breakfast: why not? Chocolate for breakfast: double why not? With 19g of protein and 8g of fiber, this breakfast is satisfying and will provide energy for a long time. Add freeze dried berries for added texture, flavor and nutrients.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) quinoa ¼ tsp. (1 ml) sea salt 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Hashbrowns - Just add water</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/breakfast-hashbrown-just-add-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/breakfast-hashbrown-just-add-water/</guid>
      <description>Hashbrowns ready in less time that needed to pack your camp in the morning!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried chives ¼ cup (60 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 4.2 oz. (119g) dehydrated hashbrowns potatoes ½ cup (125 ml) dried bell peppers 1 tbsp dried marjolam  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water 2 1-quart mylar bags 2 clips to hold the mylar bags closed Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Spiced Breakfast Quinoa</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-spiced-quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-spiced-quinoa/</guid>
      <description>Quinoa for breakfast: why not? With 18g of protein and 8g of fiber, this breakfast is satisfying and will provide energy for a long time.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) quinoa ¼ tsp. (1 ml) sea salt 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ⅓ cup (80 ml) dried apples ½ tsp (2 ml) cinnamon 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Pancakes</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Treat yourself on lazy automn backcountry mornings with these delicious sweet pumpkin pancakes!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) all-purpose flour ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp. (30 ml) pumpkin powder 1 tsp. (5 ml) pumpkin spices 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder 2 tsp. (10 ml) granulated sugar 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Pearl Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/tropical_pearl_couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/tropical_pearl_couscous/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) Pearl Couscous(also called &amp;ldquo;Israeli Couscous&amp;rdquo;) ⅓ cup (80 ml) dried tropical fruits * ⅓ cup (80 ml) whole milk powder 1 tbsp (15 ml) sweetened coconut flakes  *I used a mix of pineapples and mangoes
Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.5 liters (6 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Strawberry Extra-Protein Pancakes</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/banana-straw-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/banana-straw-pancake/</guid>
      <description>These pancakes contain 5g of protein more than our other pancake recipe, thanks to the generous amounts of whole milk powder and dehydrated eggs.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) all-purpose flour ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried strawberries and bananas 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trail Cranberry Orange Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/trail-cranberry-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/trail-cranberry-muffins/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever considered baking on the trail? It is totally possible, given you have some time available and you don&amp;rsquo;t mind carrying more fuel for your stove. But if you have cravings for baked goods while on the trail, it is totally worth it!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) all-purpose flour ¼ cup (60 ml) quick oats ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Breakfast Casserole</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</guid>
      <description>This recipe combines savory and sweet tastes for a perfect breakfast. With 25g of proteins, it is a satisfying breakfast.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp (30 ml) 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dried sweet potato dices 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) ¼ tsp (1 ml) of each: dried rosemary and salt ½ tsp (2 ml) paprika 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt ¾ tsp (3 ml) chili powder  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 8 cups (2 liters) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Extra-Chocolate Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Extra chocolate (cocoa + white chocolate chips) makes this oatmeal deliciously rich and creamy. Treat yourself with this filling and satisfying breakfast to start a long day in the outdoors.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried strawberries 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berries and Granola on-the-go</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</guid>
      <description>The freeze-dried berries bring a nice freshness to this quick breakfast recipe. High in protein (21g/serving) and ridiculously easy to make on the trail, this breakfast will allow you an early start on the trail. Substitute the skim milk powder by full-fat milk powder (e.g. Nido) to add 80 calories to your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) homemade chocolate granola 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Cranberry Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</guid>
      <description>Couscous for breakfast? Why not! With orange zest and orange flavored cranberry, it is literally a feast! It is as easy as oatmeal to prepare and it makes a nice change.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) medium couscous 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) orange flavored dried cranberries 4 tbsp. (60 ml) sliced roasted almonds 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry and Cocoa Nibs Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Cocoa nibs provide a nice crunch to this oatmeal as well as balancing perfectly the sweetness of raspberries. This oatmeal will sustain you for hours with 28g of protein and 15g of fiber per serving.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Cheese and Ham Bread</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cheese-ham-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cheese-ham-bread/</guid>
      <description>A slice of bread that contains 18g of proteins? Yeap, and it tastes delicious! This bread is moist but dense enough to travel well in a backpack. For those who worry that making bread is complicated, this recipe will prove you the contrary! The fat from the cheese keeps this bread moist for 4 to 5 days if well wrapped.
Ingredients  8.8 oz (250 g) black forest ham, cut in small cubes 1 tbsp (15 ml) olive oil 3½ cup (875 ml) all-purpose flour ¾ tsp (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s French Toasts</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Perfect for these laid-back mornings when watching the sunrise while sipping your coffee and enjoying a delicious breakfast is more important than hitting the trail early! Feel free to add your personal twist by changing the toppings: walnuts + honey or cranberries + white chocolate + macademia nuts. Just make sure to include nuts or seeds to bump the energy (calorie) content of your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and Pecan Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-pecan-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-pecan-muffins/</guid>
      <description>If you went apple picking and you want to use these apples to fuel your next outdoor adventure, this recipe is for you! These muffins are dense enough to keep their shape if stored at the bottom of your backpack but still very moist.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) brown sugar 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oatmeal 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and Peppers Egg Scramble with Hashbrowns</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is very filling with a surprising 26g of protein per serving. It is also delicious and a nice change from the sweet breakfast options.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried chives 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pancake</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Pancakes are delicious at home and even better on the trail. Topped with real maple syrup and it is pretty close to perfection. Add a fresh coffee and you are in breakfast paradise!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅔ cup (150 ml) all-purpose flour 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 4 tbsp. (60 ml) real maple syrup 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-banana oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This delicious and somewhat special oatmeal (chocolate for breakfast!) is filling with 18g of protein and 9g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1½ cup (375 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) coconut milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) cocoa powder ½ cup (125 ml) banana chips ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Egg and Hashbrowns Skillet</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</guid>
      <description>If you like bacon, you’ll love this recipe! It is filling, with 18g of protein per serving, it is a good way to start a day in the outdoors!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried chives ⅓ cup (80 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 3 tbsp. (45 ml) canola oil 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Granola</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</guid>
      <description>Are your breakfasts always the same and boring? Not anymore with this recipe of chocolate granola. Hey yes, a recipe with chocolate created by a dietitian for breakfast! And in extra, this granola is fortified in protein for long lasting satiety.
Each portion of 3&amp;frasl;4 cup contains 9g of protein and is low in fat. Add Greek yogurt or cottage cheese and fruits (I chose frozen raspberry and cherries for this picture) to this granola to make a complete meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange, Dark Chocolate and Sweet Potato Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</guid>
      <description>These delicious muffins are a good option for breakfast-on-the-go when driving to the mountains early in the morning. Bring a fruit and a portion of milk or drinkable yogurt for a more complete breakfast!
Alternatively, these muffins can be a good snack for a low-intensity training.
Ingredients  1 small sweet potato, peeled and cut in medium pieces 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini, Lemon and Blueberries Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</guid>
      <description>If you have a garden that produces an impressive quantity of zucchinis and that you don’t know what to do with them at this point, this recipe is for you!
As usual, I tested this recipe in the outdoor. Since it makes a dozen, I brought them on several adventures: from rock climbing to hiking on different trails in Washington State.
Sweet and satisfying these muffins make a good snack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>