<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Low Water on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>http://gourmethiking.com/tags/low-water/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Low Water on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gourmethiking.com/tags/low-water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Egg and Hashbrowns Skillet</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</guid>
      <description>If you like bacon, you’ll love this recipe! It is filling, with 18g of protein per serving, it is a good way to start a day in the outdoors!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried chives ⅓ cup (80 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 3 tbsp. (45 ml) canola oil 4.2 oz. (119g) of dehydrated hashbrowns potatoes* salt and pepper   * I used the brand “Golden Grill”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar   Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**   * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients  1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds   Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Granola</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</guid>
      <description>Are your breakfasts always the same and boring? Not anymore with this recipe of chocolate granola. Hey yes, a recipe with chocolate created by a dietitian for breakfast! And in extra, this granola is fortified in protein for long lasting satiety.
Each portion of 3&amp;frasl;4 cup contains 9g of protein and is low in fat. Add Greek yogurt or cottage cheese and fruits (I chose frozen raspberry and cherries for this picture) to this granola to make a complete meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa and Peanut Butter Energy Balls</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls were a success on a backcountry ski trip! They are low-fat and are packed with carbohydrates for energy during the long grueling skin up sections.
Ingredients  ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats ⅓ cup (80 ml) powdered peanut butter* 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa   * I used the PB2 powdered peanut butter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 c roasted hazelnuts ¼ c cocoa   Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange, Dark Chocolate and Sweet Potato Muffins</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</guid>
      <description>These delicious muffins are a good option for breakfast-on-the-go when driving to the mountains early in the morning. Bring a fruit and a portion of milk or drinkable yogurt for a more complete breakfast!
Alternatively, these muffins can be a good snack for a low-intensity training.
Ingredients  1 small sweet potato, peeled and cut in medium pieces 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin and Spices Cookies</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-spices-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-spices-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Sweet and satisfying, these cookies will be the perfect partners for your next hiking or long bike ride. Rich in carbohydrate, they will provide the fuel you need for your next outdoor adventure. Their protein and fiber content will make you fill full until your next stop.
Vincent and I tested these cookies on a climb of Mt. St. Helens, WA. The cookies were even better on the mountain than in my kitchen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini, Lemon and Blueberries Muffins</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</guid>
      <description>If you have a garden that produces an impressive quantity of zucchinis and that you don’t know what to do with them at this point, this recipe is for you!
As usual, I tested this recipe in the outdoor. Since it makes a dozen, I brought them on several adventures: from rock climbing to hiking on different trails in Washington State.
Sweet and satisfying these muffins make a good snack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>