<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>One Pot on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/one-pot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in One Pot on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/one-pot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Curry Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/curry-coconut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/curry-coconut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This noodle dish contains a rich and generous broth. It is an hybrid between a soup and a traditional noodle dish. Quick to prepare on the trail as it only requires boiling water to rehydrate, it will not disappoint. And bonus: very little dishes to clean!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (2 oz) 60 g thin rice vermicelli (like the ones for spring rolls) ¼ cup ( 60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* 1 tbsp (15 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried carrots 2 tsp (10 ml) dried chives 1 tbsp (15 ml) yellow curry powder 2 tsp (10 ml) vegetable broth powder 1 tsp (5 ml) sugar ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder  Equipment  Stove + fuel 1-quart mylar bag Clip or tape to close the mylar bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Chocolate Breakfast Quinoa</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-quinoa/</guid>
      <description>Quinoa for breakfast: why not? Chocolate for breakfast: double why not? With 19g of protein and 8g of fiber, this breakfast is satisfying and will provide energy for a long time. Add freeze dried berries for added texture, flavor and nutrients.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) quinoa ¼ tsp. (1 ml) sea salt 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Salt Caramel Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sea-salt-caramel-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sea-salt-caramel-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Perfect sweet and salty combination to finish a backpacking day!
Ingredients  ¼ tsp. sea salt 3 tbsp. (45 ml) instant caramel pudding mix 3 tbsp. (45 ml) powdered skim milk 2 biscottis (optional)  Equipment  Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the bag, no judgement here!) Spork or spoon  Before trip  Mix in plastic bag #1: sea salt, pudding mix and powdered skim milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Spiced Breakfast Quinoa</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-spiced-quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-spiced-quinoa/</guid>
      <description>Quinoa for breakfast: why not? With 18g of protein and 8g of fiber, this breakfast is satisfying and will provide energy for a long time.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) quinoa ¼ tsp. (1 ml) sea salt 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ⅓ cup (80 ml) dried apples ½ tsp (2 ml) cinnamon 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavors, this autumnal curry will satisfy hungry backpackers with 28.2 g of protein per servings! Pretty good for a vegan dish!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) curry powder 2 tsp (10 ml) pumpkin spices ½ tsp (2 ml) fennel seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) vegetable broth powder 1 tbsp (15 ml) pumpkin powder ½ cup (120 ml) red lentils (also called &amp;ldquo;coral&amp;rdquo; lentils) ⅓ cup (80 ml) long grain rice 1 package (5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Pancakes</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Treat yourself on lazy automn backcountry mornings with these delicious sweet pumpkin pancakes!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) all-purpose flour ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp. (30 ml) pumpkin powder 1 tsp. (5 ml) pumpkin spices 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder 2 tsp. (10 ml) granulated sugar 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Pearl Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/tropical_pearl_couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/tropical_pearl_couscous/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) Pearl Couscous(also called &amp;ldquo;Israeli Couscous&amp;rdquo;) ⅓ cup (80 ml) dried tropical fruits * ⅓ cup (80 ml) whole milk powder ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese 1 tbsp (15 ml) sweetened coconut flakes  *I used a mix of pineapples and mangoes
Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Chicken Chowder</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</guid>
      <description>This chowder with southwest notes makes a consistent meal with 40g of protein per serving. Perfect to warm up on chilly evenings.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried corn 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 1 tbsp (15 ml) chicken broth powder ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ¼ tsp (1 ml) drief thyme ¼ tsp (1 ml) black pepper 2 tbsp (30 ml) ghee ¾ cup (175 ml) whole milk powder 2 ½ tbsp (37 ml) cornstarch  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Strawberry Extra-Protein Pancakes</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/banana-straw-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/banana-straw-pancake/</guid>
      <description>These pancakes contain 5g of protein more than our other pancake recipe, thanks to the generous amounts of whole milk powder and dehydrated eggs.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) all-purpose flour ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried strawberries and bananas 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miso and Edamame Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup makes a perfect appetizer and kick-starts the rehydration process after a long day on the trail.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 individual packs of instant miso soup 60 g (2 oz) rice noodles 1 package (20g) freeze dried edamame  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1 liter (4 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s Jambalaya</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</guid>
      <description>If you like spicy food, this recipe will become a backpacking favorite. Packed with proteins, this recipe brings good satiety for a relatively low calorie count. Long distance backpackers, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare both servings for yourself! And if you have some leftovers of chorizo, it makes a great addition to your lunch the following day.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Breakfast Casserole</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</guid>
      <description>This recipe combines savory and sweet tastes for a perfect breakfast. With 25g of proteins, it is a satisfying breakfast.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp (30 ml) 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dried sweet potato dices 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) ¼ tsp (1 ml) of each: dried rosemary and salt ½ tsp (2 ml) paprika 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt ¾ tsp (3 ml) chili powder  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 8 cups (2 liters) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight Rosé Sauce Tortellinis</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried tomato powder* ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried spinach ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil  *You can also use some tomato paste in tube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Curry Rice Vermicelli</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</guid>
      <description>This one-pot recipe is rich in flavors and in carbohydrates! It will provide the energy needed to recharge the batteries in prevision for a long day of backpacking.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 oz (90g) thin rice vermicelli ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried mixed vegetables ¼ cup (60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Extra-Chocolate Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Extra chocolate (cocoa + white chocolate chips) makes this oatmeal deliciously rich and creamy. Treat yourself with this filling and satisfying breakfast to start a long day in the outdoors.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried strawberries 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley and Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</guid>
      <description>This super-easy-to-make soup is the perfect way to rehydrate after a long day in the outdoors. It does not contain enough energy (only 112 calories) for a dinner but is the perfect appetizer!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp. (30 ml) 10 minute barley 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried parsley 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms 1&amp;frasl;2 cube of beef broth (for the equivalent of 1 cup of broth)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berries and Granola on-the-go</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</guid>
      <description>The freeze-dried berries bring a nice freshness to this quick breakfast recipe. High in protein (21g/serving) and ridiculously easy to make on the trail, this breakfast will allow you an early start on the trail. Substitute the skim milk powder by full-fat milk powder (e.g. Nido) to add 80 calories to your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) homemade chocolate granola 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight High-Calorie Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</guid>
      <description>The perfect comfort food, this mac&amp;amp;cheese is creamy, rich and made with real (freeze dried) cheddar cheese. When calorie needs are high and space limited in your packs, don&amp;rsquo;t look further!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) macaroni ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried chives ¼ cup (60 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Cranberry Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</guid>
      <description>Couscous for breakfast? Why not! With orange zest and orange flavored cranberry, it is literally a feast! It is as easy as oatmeal to prepare and it makes a nice change.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) medium couscous 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) orange flavored dried cranberries 4 tbsp. (60 ml) sliced roasted almonds 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garam Masala Chickpea Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>You will start to enjoy this dish before even eating it. Just the smell that comes from the pot while cooking is enough to boost your appetite! Make it vegan by using a vegetable broth instead or add calories by incorporating canola oil.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 tbsp (45 ml) basmati rice 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ tsp (1 ml) coriander seeds, grounded 1½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry and Vanilla Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Dessert is always good and even more on the trail. Add 10g of protein to your meal by adding this delicious dessert. Top this pudding with fresh blueberries found on the side of the trail, when in season, for extra nutrients and antioxidants. Replace powdered skim milk instead by full-fat milk for extra calories.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) dried blueberries 1 large graham cookie, crushed 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry and Cocoa Nibs Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Cocoa nibs provide a nice crunch to this oatmeal as well as balancing perfectly the sweetness of raspberries. This oatmeal will sustain you for hours with 28g of protein and 15g of fiber per serving.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s French Toasts</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Perfect for these laid-back mornings when watching the sunrise while sipping your coffee and enjoying a delicious breakfast is more important than hitting the trail early! Feel free to add your personal twist by changing the toppings: walnuts + honey or cranberries + white chocolate + macademia nuts. Just make sure to include nuts or seeds to bump the energy (calorie) content of your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Mushroom Egg Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</guid>
      <description>Perfect recipe for mushroom lovers! Rich and creamy, this dish is the perfect comfort food on a chilly backpacking night. Technically, this recipe is not vegetarian because of the beef broth added to it but it can easily be changed for a vegetable broth.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 ½ cups (875 ml) dry egg noodles ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) dried chanterelle mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) 1 cube beef broth 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried tarragon 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried chives Black pepper to taste 1 can (225 ml) Table Cream by Nestlé(thick cream)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Dried Tomato and Basil Pesto Tortellini</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) ½ cup (125 ml) sun dried tomatoes ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) basil pesto, in a tube ¼ cup ( 60 ml) pine nuts, roasted  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pancake</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Pancakes are delicious at home and even better on the trail. Topped with real maple syrup and it is pretty close to perfection. Add a fresh coffee and you are in breakfast paradise!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅔ cup (150 ml) all-purpose flour 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 4 tbsp. (60 ml) real maple syrup 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate and Raspberries Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 2 Oreo cookies, crushed 3 tbsp. (45 ml) instant chocolate pudding mix 3 tbsp. (45 ml) powdered skim milk  Equipment  Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the bag, no judgement here!) Spork or spoon  Before trip  Mix in plastic bag #1: raspberries and Oreo cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-banana oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This delicious and somewhat special oatmeal (chocolate for breakfast!) is filling with 18g of protein and 9g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1½ cup (375 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) coconut milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) cocoa powder ½ cup (125 ml) banana chips ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Salmon Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 ½ cups (625 ml) dry pasta (I used penne) ½ cup (125 ml) dried bell peppers 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried chives ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ½ cup (125 ml) powdered milk 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried dill Black pepper to taste 1 Alfredo sauce package(I used the brand Knorr) 2 packages of smoked salmon jerky(2 x 3oz)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hot Chocolate</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>Warm, sweet and rich, this basic hot chocolate recipe will help you to relax after a long day of adventuring. This drink contains 12g of high-quality protein, which is 11g more than your commercial hot chocolate powder prepared with hot water! It also provides some quickly absorbed carbohydrates and liquids to kickstart the recovery process.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) sugar 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa 4 tbsp. (60 ml) powdered milk pinch of salt  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Cup to drink Sporks or forks  Before trip  Mix all the ingredients together  At camp  Bring to boil about 1 cup (250 ml) of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp and Rosé Sauce Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups (500 ml) dry pasta (I used macaroni) 1 can (4 oz – 113g) of shrimp 1 can (6 oz – 170 g) of tomato paste (personally I took one with added herbs for extra flavor!) 3 tbsp (45 ml) powdered milk ½ cup Parmesan cheese 1 tsp (5 ml) dried herbs (I mixed oregano and basil) ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used green peas, corn, tomatoes and spinach)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Can opener Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, not judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>