<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>One Pot on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/one-pot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in One Pot on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/one-pot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s French Toasts</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Perfect for these laid-back mornings when watching the sunrise while sipping your coffee and enjoying a delicious breakfast is more important than hitting the trail early! Feel free to add your personal twist by changing the toppings: walnuts + honey or cranberries + white chocolate + macademia nuts. Just make sure to include nuts or seeds to bump the energy (calorie) content of your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients  (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Mushroom Egg Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</guid>
      <description>Perfect recipe for mushroom lovers! Rich and creamy, this dish is the perfect comfort food on a chilly backpacking night. Technically, this recipe is not vegetarian because of the beef broth added to it but it can easily be changed for a vegetable broth.
Ingredients  3 ½ cups (875 ml) dry egg noodles ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze-dried white mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) dried chanterelle mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) 1 cube beef broth 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried tarragon 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried chives Black pepper to taste 1 can (225 ml) of Nestlé Media Crema Table (thick cream)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Dried Tomato and Basil Pesto Tortellini</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) ½ cup (125 ml) sun dried tomatoes ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) basil pesto, in a tube ¼ cup ( 60 ml) pine nuts, roasted  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pancake</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Pancakes are delicious at home and even better on the trail. Topped with real maple syrup and it is pretty close to perfection. Add a fresh coffee and you are in breakfast paradise!
Ingredients  ⅔ cup (150 ml) all-purpose flour 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried whole eggs 4 tbsp. (60 ml) real maple syrup 2 tsp. (10 ml) baking powder ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries 1 pinch of salt 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate and Raspberries Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 2 Oreo cookies, crushed 3 tbsp. (45 ml) instant chocolate pudding mix 3 tbsp. (45 ml) powdered skim milk  Equipment  Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the bag, no judgement here!) Spork or spoon  Before trip  Mix in plastic bag #1: raspberries and Oreo cookies. Mix in plastic bag #2: pudding mix and powdered skim milk  At camp  Add ½ cup (125 ml) of cold water to bag # 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried tomatoes 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-banana oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This delicious and somewhat special oatmeal (chocolate for breakfast!) is filling with 18g of protein and 9g of fiber.
Ingredients  1½ cup (375 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) coconut milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) cocoa powder ½ cup (125 ml) banana chips ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 3 tbsp. (45 ml) sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowls to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Salmon Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 ½ cups (625 ml) dry pasta (I used penne) ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated bell peppers 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried chives ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ½ cup (125 ml) powdered milk 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried dill Black pepper to taste 1 Alfredo sauce package (I used the brand Knorr) 2 packages of smoked salmon jerky (2 x 3oz)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hot Chocolate</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>Warm, sweet and rich, this basic hot chocolate recipe will help you to relax after a long day of adventuring. This drink contains 12g of high-quality protein, which is 11g more than your commercial hot chocolate powder prepared with hot water! It also provides some quickly absorbed carbohydrates and liquids to kickstart the recovery process.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) sugar 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa 4 tbsp. (60 ml) powdered milk pinch of salt  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Cup to drink Sporks or forks  Before trip  Mix all the ingredients together  At camp  Bring to boil about 1 cup (250 ml) of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) black bean pasta (I used Black Bean Rotini by Trader Joe’s) ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze-dried corn ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated tomatoes ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated carrots 4 tsp (20 ml) chicken broth powder* 1 tbsp (15 ml) chili powder 1 tsp (5 ml) paprika 2 tsp (10 ml) onion powder ½ tsp (2 ml) garlic powder ½ tsp (2 ml) coriander seeds, grounded ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin, grounded 2 tbsp (30 ml) tomato paste** 2 6-inch (15 cm) tortillas  *Want to make it vegan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp and Rosé Sauce Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups (500 ml) dry pasta (I used macaroni) 1 can (4 oz – 113g) of shrimp 1 can (6 oz – 170 g) of tomato paste (personally I took one with added herbs for extra flavor!) 3 tbsp (45 ml) powdered milk ½ cup Parmesan cheese 1 tsp (5 ml) dried herbs (I mixed oregano and basil) ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used green peas, corn, tomatoes and spinach)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Can opener Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, not judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>