<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>One Pot on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>http://gourmethiking.com/tags/one-pot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in One Pot on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gourmethiking.com/tags/one-pot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) black bean pasta (I used Black Bean Rotini by Trader Joe’s) ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze-dried corn ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated tomatoes ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated carrots 4 tsp (20 ml) chicken broth powder* 1 tbsp (15 ml) chili powder 1 tsp (5 ml) paprika 2 tsp (10 ml) onion powder ½ tsp (2 ml) garlic powder ½ tsp (2 ml) coriander seeds, grounded ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin, grounded 2 tbsp (30 ml) tomato paste** 2 6-inch (15 cm) tortillas   *Want to make it vegan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar   Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp and Rosé Sauce Pasta</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups (500 ml) dry pasta (I used macaroni) 1 can (4 oz – 113g) of shrimp 1 can (6 oz – 170 g) of tomato paste (personally I took one with added herbs for extra flavor!) 3 tbsp (45 ml) powdered milk ½ cup Parmesan cheese 1 tsp (5 ml) dried herbs (I mixed oregano and basil) ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used green peas, corn, tomatoes and spinach)   Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Can opener Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, not judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>