<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dinner on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/dinner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dinner on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/dinner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alfredo Chicken Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/alfredo-chicken-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/alfredo-chicken-pasta/</guid>
      <description>This high-calorie meal is perfect to refuel after a long day of adventuring. Tasty and filling, without being overly heavy. Try it and you&amp;rsquo;ll adopt it!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
¾ cup (175 ml) dry macaroni ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried broccoli ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried chicken ⅓ cup (80 ml) shelf-stable shredded parmesan 3 tbsp (45 ml) heavy cream powder ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Curry Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/curry-coconut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/curry-coconut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This noodle dish contains a rich and generous broth. It is an hybrid between a soup and a traditional noodle dish. Quick to prepare on the trail as it only requires boiling water to rehydrate, it will not disappoint. And bonus: very little dishes to clean!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
(2 oz) 60 g thin rice vermicelli (like the ones for spring rolls) ¼ cup ( 60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) * 1 tbsp (15 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried carrots 2 tsp (10 ml) dried chives 1 tbsp (15 ml) yellow curry powder 2 tsp (10 ml) vegetable broth powder 1 tsp (5 ml) sugar ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder Equipment Stove + fuel 1-quart mylar bag Clip or tape to close the mylar bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-lentil-curry-copy/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavors, this autumnal curry will satisfy hungry backpackers with 28.2 g of protein per servings! Pretty good for a vegan dish!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
1 tbsp (15 ml) curry powder 2 tsp (10 ml) pumpkin spices ½ tsp (2 ml) fennel seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) vegetable broth powder 1 tbsp (15 ml) [pumpkin powder](/blog-post/pumpkin-powder) ½ cup (120 ml) red lentils (also called &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Chicken Chowder</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</guid>
      <description>This chowder with southwest notes makes a consistent meal with 40g of protein per serving. Perfect to warm up on chilly evenings.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
1 tbsp (15 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers (I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried corn 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 1 tbsp (15 ml) chicken broth powder ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ¼ tsp (1 ml) dried thyme ¼ tsp (1 ml) black pepper 2 tbsp (30 ml) ghee ¾ cup (175 ml) whole milk powder 2 ½ tbsp (37 ml) cornstarch Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miso and Edamame Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup makes a perfect appetizer and kick-starts the rehydration process after a long day on the trail.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
2 individual packs of instant miso soup 60 g (2 oz) rice noodles 1 package (20g) freeze dried edamame Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1 liter (4 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s Jambalaya</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</guid>
      <description>If you like spicy food, this recipe will become a backpacking favorite. Packed with proteins, this recipe brings good satiety for a relatively low calorie count. Long distance backpackers, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare both servings for yourself! And if you have some leftovers of chorizo, it makes a great addition to your lunch the following day.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
½ cup (120 ml) rice 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers (I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 tsp (5 ml) chicken broth powder ½ tsp (2 ml) of each: garlic powder, dried oregano and paprika ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ½ tbsp (7 ml) dried tomato powder 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 5 oz (150g) dry chorizo sausage Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Knife to cut the chorizo Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight Rosé Sauce Tortellinis</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried tomato powder\* ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried spinach ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil *You can also use some tomato paste in tube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morrocan Apricot Chickpeas</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</guid>
      <description>Warm, comforting and sweet, this dish will transport your taste buds somewhere else. Perfect to add variety to your backpacking meals. And you will not believe that this vegan recipe contains 28g of proteins and 6.1 mg of iron (thanks to the dried apricots for this nice contribution!)
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
½ cup (125 ml) dry couscous salt and pepper, to taste 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ cup (60 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated apricots, chopped in small cubes ½ tsp (2 ml) ground coriander seeds ½ tsp (2 ml) ground ginger ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin ¼ tsp (1 ml) cinnamon ¼ tsp (1 ml) paprika ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt 1 pinch of cayenne pepper ⅓ cup (80 ml) roasted almonds Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Curry Rice Vermicelli</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</guid>
      <description>This one-pot recipe is rich in flavors and in carbohydrates! It will provide the energy needed to recharge the batteries in prevision for a long day of backpacking.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
3 oz (90g) thin rice vermicelli ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried mixed vegetables ¼ cup (60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley and Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</guid>
      <description>This super-easy-to-make soup is the perfect way to rehydrate after a long day in the outdoors. It does not contain enough energy (only 112 calories) for a dinner but is the perfect appetizer!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
2 tbsp. (30 ml) 10 minute barley 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried parsley 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms 1/2 cube of beef broth (for the equivalent of 1 cup of broth) Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight High-Calorie Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight-mac-cheese/</guid>
      <description>The perfect comfort food, this mac&amp;amp;cheese is creamy, rich and made with real (freeze dried) cheddar cheese. When calorie needs are high and space limited in your packs, don&amp;rsquo;t look further!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
1 cup (250 ml) macaroni ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried chives ¼ cup (60 ml) whole milk powder 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garam Masala Chickpea Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>You will start to enjoy this dish before even eating it. Just the smell that comes from the pot while cooking is enough to boost your appetite! Make it vegan by using a vegetable broth instead or add calories by incorporating canola oil.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
3 tbsp (45 ml) basmati rice 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ tsp (1 ml) coriander seeds, grounded 1½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
(5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) * ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed ** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s) Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Mushroom Egg Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/creamy-mushroom-noodles/</guid>
      <description>Perfect recipe for mushroom lovers! Rich and creamy, this dish is the perfect comfort food on a chilly backpacking night. Technically, this recipe is not vegetarian because of the beef broth added to it but it can easily be changed for a vegetable broth.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
3 ½ cups (875 ml) dry egg noodles ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) dried chanterelle mushrooms ¾ cup (175 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) 1 cube beef broth 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried tarragon 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried chives Black pepper to taste 1 can (225 ml) Table Cream by Nestlé (thick cream) Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Dried Tomato and Basil Pesto Tortellini</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) ½ cup (125 ml) sun dried tomatoes ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) basil pesto, in a tube ¼ cup ( 60 ml) pine nuts, roasted Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Alfredo Gnocchi</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavor (and in calories!), this recipe is perfect for these difficult overnight backpacking trips.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
1 package of 17.6 oz (500g) gnocchi 3.25 oz. (92g) pre-cooked bacon 1 can 7.6 fl. oz. (225 ml) table cream (I used Table Cream by Nestlé) 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried chives 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried parsley ⅓ cup (80 ml) parmigiano reggiano, shredded ¼ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregano, Tomato and Sausage Orzo</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is perfect for overnight backpacking trips or when weight and space in your backpacks are not issues.
Ingredients 2 tbsp. (30 ml) olive oil 2 packages of cooked chicken sausages (12 oz or 340g each)* 2 cups (500 ml) dry orzo ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used a mix) 1 tsp. (10 ml) dried oregano leaves 4.5 oz (127 g) double-concentrated tomato paste. *If you are worried about food safety, you can freeze the sausages prior to your trip and pack them frozen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Salmon Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
2 ½ cups (625 ml) dry pasta (I used penne) ½ cup (125 ml) dried bell peppers 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried chives ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ½ cup (125 ml) powdered milk 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried dill Black pepper to taste 1 Alfredo sauce package (I used the brand Knorr) 2 packages of smoked salmon jerky (2 x 3oz) Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp and Rosé Sauce Pasta</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 cups (500 ml) dry pasta (I used macaroni) 1 can (4 oz – 113g) of shrimp 1 can (6 oz – 170 g) of tomato paste (personally I took one with added herbs for extra flavor!) 3 tbsp (45 ml) powdered milk ½ cup Parmesan cheese 1 tsp (5 ml) dried herbs (I mixed oregano and basil) ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used green peas, corn, tomatoes and spinach) Equipment Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Can opener Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, not judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
