<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinner on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>http://gourmethiking.com/tags/dinner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dinner on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gourmethiking.com/tags/dinner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Dried Tomato and Basil Pesto Tortellini</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) ½ cup (125 ml) sun dried tomatoes ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) basil pesto, in a tube ¼ cup ( 60 ml) pine nuts, roasted   Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Alfredo Gnocchi</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/bacon-alfredo-gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Rich in flavor (and in calories!), this recipe is perfect for these difficult overnight backpacking trips.
Ingredients  1 package of 17.6 oz (500g) gnocchi 3.25 oz. (92g) pre-cooked bacon 1 can 7.6 fl. oz. (225 ml) table cream (I used Table Cream by Nestlé) 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried chives 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried parsley ⅓ cup (80 ml) parmigiano reggiano, shredded ¼ tsp. (1 ml) salt ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregano, Tomato and Sausage Orzo</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is perfect for overnight backpacking trips or when weight and space in your backpacks are not issues.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) olive oil 2 packages of cooked chicken sausages (12 oz or 340g each)* 2 cups (500 ml) dry orzo ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables ( I used a mix) 1 tsp. (10 ml) dried oregano leaves 4.5 oz (127 g) double-concentrated tomato paste.   *If you are worried about food safety, you can freeze the sausages prior to your trip and pack them frozen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried tomatoes 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Salmon Pasta</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/smoked-salmon-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 ½ cups (625 ml) dry pasta (I used penne) ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated bell peppers 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried chives ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ½ cup (125 ml) powdered milk 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried dill Black pepper to taste 1 Alfredo sauce package (I used the brand Knorr) 2 packages of smoked salmon jerky (2 x 3oz)   Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) black bean pasta (I used Black Bean Rotini by Trader Joe’s) ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze-dried corn ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated tomatoes ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated carrots 4 tsp (20 ml) chicken broth powder* 1 tbsp (15 ml) chili powder 1 tsp (5 ml) paprika 2 tsp (10 ml) onion powder ½ tsp (2 ml) garlic powder ½ tsp (2 ml) coriander seeds, grounded ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin, grounded 2 tbsp (30 ml) tomato paste** 2 6-inch (15 cm) tortillas   *Want to make it vegan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli and Salmon Mac&amp;Cheese</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/broccoli-salmon-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Forget the Mac&amp;amp;Cheese mix in a box. This recipe is rich and provides a generous amount of vegetables (quite rare in backpacking!). The high content in protein (48g/serving) will provide a long lasting satiety sensation. The high carbohydrate content will replenish your muscle glycogen and will prepare you for more adventures on the following day. The relatively short list of ingredients makes it easy to prepare at home and on the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp and Rosé Sauce Pasta</title>
      <link>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gourmethiking.com/recipes/shrimp-and-rose-sauce-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups (500 ml) dry pasta (I used macaroni) 1 can (4 oz – 113g) of shrimp 1 can (6 oz – 170 g) of tomato paste (personally I took one with added herbs for extra flavor!) 3 tbsp (45 ml) powdered milk ½ cup Parmesan cheese 1 tsp (5 ml) dried herbs (I mixed oregano and basil) ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used green peas, corn, tomatoes and spinach)   Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Can opener Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, not judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>