<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dairy Free on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/dairy-free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dairy Free on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/dairy-free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Chicken Chowder</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</guid>
      <description>This chowder with southwest notes makes a consistent meal with 40g of protein per serving. Perfect to warm up on chilly evenings.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried corn 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 1 tbsp (15 ml) chicken broth powder ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ¼ tsp (1 ml) drief thyme ¼ tsp (1 ml) black pepper 2 tbsp (30 ml) ghee ¾ cup (175 ml) whole milk powder 2 ½ tbsp (37 ml) cornstarch  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miso and Edamame Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup makes a perfect appetizer and kick-starts the rehydration process after a long day on the trail.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 individual packs of instant miso soup 60 g (2 oz) rice noodles 1 package (20g) freeze dried edamame  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1 liter (4 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s Jambalaya</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/jambalaya/</guid>
      <description>If you like spicy food, this recipe will become a backpacking favorite. Packed with proteins, this recipe brings good satiety for a relatively low calorie count. Long distance backpackers, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare both servings for yourself! And if you have some leftovers of chorizo, it makes a great addition to your lunch the following day.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morrocan Apricot Chickpeas</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</guid>
      <description>Warm, comforting and sweet, this dish will transport your taste buds somewhere else. Perfect to add variety to your backpacking meals. And you will not believe that this vegan recipe contains 28g of proteins and 6.1 mg of iron (thanks to the dried apricots for this nice contribution!)
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry couscous salt and pepper, to taste 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ cup (60 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated apricots, chopped in small cubes ½ tsp (2 ml) ground coriander seeds ½ tsp (2 ml) ground ginger ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin ¼ tsp (1 ml) cinnamon ¼ tsp (1 ml) paprika ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt 1 pinch of cayenne pepper ⅓ cup (80 ml) roasted almonds  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Curry Rice Vermicelli</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</guid>
      <description>This one-pot recipe is rich in flavors and in carbohydrates! It will provide the energy needed to recharge the batteries in prevision for a long day of backpacking.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 oz (90g) thin rice vermicelli ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried mixed vegetables ¼ cup (60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley and Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</guid>
      <description>This super-easy-to-make soup is the perfect way to rehydrate after a long day in the outdoors. It does not contain enough energy (only 112 calories) for a dinner but is the perfect appetizer!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp. (30 ml) 10 minute barley 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried parsley 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms 1&amp;frasl;2 cube of beef broth (for the equivalent of 1 cup of broth)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garam Masala Chickpea Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/garam_masala_chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>You will start to enjoy this dish before even eating it. Just the smell that comes from the pot while cooking is enough to boost your appetite! Make it vegan by using a vegetable broth instead or add calories by incorporating canola oil.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 tbsp (45 ml) basmati rice 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried green peas ⅓ cup (80 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ tsp (1 ml) coriander seeds, grounded 1½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Maple Energetic Gummies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-gummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-gummies/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect snack for high intensity workouts. Going for a stairs training, an interval running session or a high-intensity ski outing? These gummies will provide quick energy as well as electrolytes to help you retain the fluids you are drinking. Can also rescue a training session or an outdoor exploration when the fuel tank gets low, you hit the wall or you bonk (whatever expression you use to describe this state of very low energy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple candied pecans and apples with sea salt sprinkles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</guid>
      <description>The fanciest of trail mixes, this mix combines sweet and salty flavors for a premium snack on the trail. It is a good option for these cold outdoor adventures when maximizing the energy density (calories/weight) is a must. It also does taste super good on day snowshoeing or backcountry skiing adventures! Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) gluten-free puffed rice 1 cup (250 ml) pecans ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ¼ cup (60 ml) real maple syrup ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and Peppers Egg Scramble with Hashbrowns</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is very filling with a surprising 26g of protein per serving. It is also delicious and a nice change from the sweet breakfast options.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried chives 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</guid>
      <description>These energy balls have a subtil coffee taste that will please the coffee lovers but are sweet enough to please the non coffee drinkers. This snack kept me going on a recent climb of Mt.Rainier that was longer than expected. I am not sure how I managed to save one energy ball to take a picture at the top&amp;hellip;
Ingredients  ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 1 ½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregano, Tomato and Sausage Orzo</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/oregano-tomato-orzo/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is perfect for overnight backpacking trips or when weight and space in your backpacks are not issues.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) olive oil 2 packages of cooked chicken sausages (12 oz or 340g each)* 2 cups (500 ml) dry orzo ⅔ cup (150 ml) dried vegetables (I used a mix) 1 tsp. (10 ml) dried oregano leaves 4.5 oz (127 g) double-concentrated tomato paste.  *If you are worried about food safety, you can freeze the sausages prior to your trip and pack them frozen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili-Type Stew</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chili-stew/</guid>
      <description>This stew is inspired by chili sin carne recipes. The black bean pasta replace beautifully beans and provide a great deal of protein and fiber to this meal. Try adding Pepper Jack Moon Cheese when serving for an extra crunchy touch and some more protein. If the long spices list is a concern for you, you can always consider using pre-mixed chili spices.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Egg and Hashbrowns Skillet</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/egg-bacon-hashbrown/</guid>
      <description>If you like bacon, you’ll love this recipe! It is filling, with 18g of protein per serving, it is a good way to start a day in the outdoors!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp. (15 ml) dried chives ⅓ cup (80 ml) real crumbled bacon (the ones for salads) 3 tbsp. (45 ml) canola oil 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**  * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa and Peanut Butter Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls were a success on a backcountry ski trip! They are low-fat and are packed with carbohydrates for energy during the long grueling skin up sections.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats ⅓ cup (80 ml) powdered peanut butter 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa  Preparation  Bring dates and water to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 cup roasted hazelnuts ¼ cup cocoa  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/indian-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Super easy recipe to cook in the outdoor that will remember you of India, wherever you are in the world! Everything can be cooked in a single pot! The high fibre (13 g/serving) and protein (23 g/serving) contents will prevent hunger from coming back too soon. Rich in carbohydrates, this meal will provide the fuel necessary to climb the highest peaks! What else can you ask for? Yummy taste? Yes, this is included too!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>