<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vegetarian on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/vegetarian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vegetarian on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/vegetarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Breakfast Casserole</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sweet-potato-casserole/</guid>
      <description>This recipe combines savory and sweet tastes for a perfect breakfast. With 25g of proteins, it is a satisfying breakfast.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp (30 ml) 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dried sweet potato dices 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) ¼ tsp (1 ml) of each: dried rosemary and salt ½ tsp (2 ml) paprika 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach ¾ cup (175 ml) freeze dried cheddar cheese ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated whole eggs ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt ¾ tsp (3 ml) chili powder  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 8 cups (2 liters) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat Sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight Rosé Sauce Tortellinis</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/ultralight_rose_sauce_tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried tomato powder* ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried spinach ½ cup (125 ml) whole milk powder ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil  *You can also use some tomato paste in tube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morrocan Apricot Chickpeas</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</guid>
      <description>Warm, comforting and sweet, this dish will transport your taste buds somewhere else. Perfect to add variety to your backpacking meals. And you will not believe that this vegan recipe contains 28g of proteins and 6.1 mg of iron (thanks to the dried apricots for this nice contribution!)
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry couscous salt and pepper, to taste 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ cup (60 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated apricots, chopped in small cubes ½ tsp (2 ml) ground coriander seeds ½ tsp (2 ml) ground ginger ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin ¼ tsp (1 ml) cinnamon ¼ tsp (1 ml) paprika ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt 1 pinch of cayenne pepper ⅓ cup (80 ml) roasted almonds  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Curry Rice Vermicelli</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/red-curry-vermicelli/</guid>
      <description>This one-pot recipe is rich in flavors and in carbohydrates! It will provide the energy needed to recharge the batteries in prevision for a long day of backpacking.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 3 oz (90g) thin rice vermicelli ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried mixed vegetables ¼ cup (60 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP) ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut milk powder 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Extra-Chocolate Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/strawberry-chocolate-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Extra chocolate (cocoa + white chocolate chips) makes this oatmeal deliciously rich and creamy. Treat yourself with this filling and satisfying breakfast to start a long day in the outdoors.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) whole milk powder ½ cup (125 ml) freeze dried strawberries 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa powder 1 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berries and Granola on-the-go</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/berries_granola/</guid>
      <description>The freeze-dried berries bring a nice freshness to this quick breakfast recipe. High in protein (21g/serving) and ridiculously easy to make on the trail, this breakfast will allow you an early start on the trail. Substitute the skim milk powder by full-fat milk powder (e.g. Nido) to add 80 calories to your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) homemade chocolate granola 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Cranberry Couscous</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-couscous/</guid>
      <description>Couscous for breakfast? Why not! With orange zest and orange flavored cranberry, it is literally a feast! It is as easy as oatmeal to prepare and it makes a nice change.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅓ cup (80 ml) medium couscous 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) orange flavored dried cranberries 4 tbsp. (60 ml) sliced roasted almonds 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry and Vanilla Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Dessert is always good and even more on the trail. Add 10g of protein to your meal by adding this delicious dessert. Top this pudding with fresh blueberries found on the side of the trail, when in season, for extra nutrients and antioxidants. Replace powdered skim milk instead by full-fat milk for extra calories.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) dried blueberries 1 large graham cookie, crushed 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry and Cocoa Nibs Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/raspberry-cocoa-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>Cocoa nibs provide a nice crunch to this oatmeal as well as balancing perfectly the sweetness of raspberries. This oatmeal will sustain you for hours with 28g of protein and 15g of fiber per serving.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 4 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expedition Molasse Cookies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/expedition-molasse-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/expedition-molasse-cookies/</guid>
      <description>These heavy-duty cookies are perfect to fuel your next expedition. They contain healthy fats (from cashew butter and chia seeds) and almost 10g of protein, which is huge for a cookie! However, these nutrition components do not undermine the taste. With a strong molasse taste and a smooth texture, these cookies will remind you ok sweet childhood memories!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) winter squash (e.g. butternut) or sweet potato puree ⅔ cup (160 ml) molasse ¾ cup (180 ml) cashew butter 2 eggs 1 tsp (5 ml) vanilla extract ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macadamia nuts, raspberries and white chocolate goodness</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/macadamia-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/macadamia-bar/</guid>
      <description>These bars will fuel your winter adventures and put a smile on your face after each bite! They stay soft even at freezing temperature, which make them easy to eat during a snowy day. Ok, they are a bit high in fat for a high intensity training but are perfect for these long outings on snowshoes or on backcountry skis.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) pitted dates, cut in small pieces 2 tbsp (30 ml) water 1 ½ cup (375 ml) frozen raspberries, divided 1 tsp (5 ml) vanilla extract 1 tsp (5 ml) baking powder 2 cups (500 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) whole wheat flour ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder ¼ cup (60 ml) sweetened shredded coconut ½ cup (125 ml) macadamia nuts 1 pinch of salt ⅔ cup (160 ml) white chocolate chips 1 tbsp (15 ml) unsalted butter  Preparation  Combine the dates, water and 1 cup (250 ml) of frozen raspberries in a small pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple candied pecans and apples with sea salt sprinkles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</guid>
      <description>The fanciest of trail mixes, this mix combines sweet and salty flavors for a premium snack on the trail. It is a good option for these cold outdoor adventures when maximizing the energy density (calories/weight) is a must. It also does taste super good on day snowshoeing or backcountry skiing adventures! Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) gluten-free puffed rice 1 cup (250 ml) pecans ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ¼ cup (60 ml) real maple syrup ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacker&#39;s French Toasts</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Perfect for these laid-back mornings when watching the sunrise while sipping your coffee and enjoying a delicious breakfast is more important than hitting the trail early! Feel free to add your personal twist by changing the toppings: walnuts + honey or cranberries + white chocolate + macademia nuts. Just make sure to include nuts or seeds to bump the energy (calorie) content of your meal.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and Pecan Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-pecan-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-pecan-muffins/</guid>
      <description>If you went apple picking and you want to use these apples to fuel your next outdoor adventure, this recipe is for you! These muffins are dense enough to keep their shape if stored at the bottom of your backpack but still very moist.
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) brown sugar 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oatmeal 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Dried Tomato and Basil Pesto Tortellini</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sundried-tortellinis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) dry tortellini (Can be found in the pasta section of most grocery stores) ½ cup (125 ml) sun dried tomatoes ¼ cup ( 60 ml) parmesan cheese ¼ cup ( 60 ml) basil pesto, in a tube ¼ cup ( 60 ml) pine nuts, roasted  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and Peppers Egg Scramble with Hashbrowns</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/spinach_pepper_egg/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is very filling with a surprising 26g of protein per serving. It is also delicious and a nice change from the sweet breakfast options.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried chives 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried spinach 2 tsp (10 ml) dried basil ½ tsp (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</guid>
      <description>These energy balls have a subtil coffee taste that will please the coffee lovers but are sweet enough to please the non coffee drinkers. This snack kept me going on a recent climb of Mt.Rainier that was longer than expected. I am not sure how I managed to save one energy ball to take a picture at the top&amp;hellip;
Ingredients  ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 1 ½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pancake</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Pancakes are delicious at home and even better on the trail. Topped with real maple syrup and it is pretty close to perfection. Add a fresh coffee and you are in breakfast paradise!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ⅔ cup (150 ml) all-purpose flour 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dehydrated whole eggs 4 tbsp. (60 ml) real maple syrup 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate and Raspberries Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 2 Oreo cookies, crushed 3 tbsp. (45 ml) instant chocolate pudding mix 3 tbsp. (45 ml) powdered skim milk  Equipment  Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the bag, no judgement here!) Spork or spoon  Before trip  Mix in plastic bag #1: raspberries and Oreo cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco-banana oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/choco-banana-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This delicious and somewhat special oatmeal (chocolate for breakfast!) is filling with 18g of protein and 9g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1½ cup (375 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) coconut milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) cocoa powder ½ cup (125 ml) banana chips ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hot Chocolate</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/hot-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>Warm, sweet and rich, this basic hot chocolate recipe will help you to relax after a long day of adventuring. This drink contains 12g of high-quality protein, which is 11g more than your commercial hot chocolate powder prepared with hot water! It also provides some quickly absorbed carbohydrates and liquids to kickstart the recovery process.
Ingredients  2 tbsp. (30 ml) sugar 1 tbsp. (15 ml) cocoa 4 tbsp. (60 ml) powdered milk pinch of salt  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Cup to drink Sporks or forks  Before trip  Mix all the ingredients together  At camp  Bring to boil about 1 cup (250 ml) of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange and Chocolate Protein Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choco-protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choco-protein/</guid>
      <description>Some Canadian friends told me these protein balls remind them of the famous Tim Hortons’ Timbits. Although these protein balls have similar taste and shape than the Timbits, their nutritional value is way more interesting with 4.7g of fiber and 9.3 g of protein per serving (2 balls).
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) orange juice 2 tsp (10 ml) fresh orange zest 3 tbsp (45 ml) cocoa 1 cup (250 ml) quick oats ¾ cup (175 ml) whey protein isolate ⅓ cup (80 ml) coconut flour, divided  Preparation  Bring dates and orange juice to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Pecan Oatmeal</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-pecan-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>This oatmeal recipe will satisfy the hungriest backpacker appetite with 19g of protein and 10g of fiber.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) quick oats 4 tbsp. (60 ml) skim milk powder 4 tbsp. (60 ml) dried blueberries 2 tbsp. (30 ml) chopped pecans 2 tbsp. (30 ml) sweetened and shredded dried coconut 1 tbsp. (15 ml) brown sugar  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot to boil water Bowl to eat sporks or forks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**  * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Granola</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/chocolate-granola/</guid>
      <description>Are your breakfasts always the same and boring? Not anymore with this recipe of chocolate granola. Hey yes, a recipe with chocolate created by a dietitian for breakfast! And in extra, this granola is fortified in protein for long lasting satiety.
Each portion of 3&amp;frasl;4 cup contains 9g of protein and is low in fat. Add Greek yogurt or cottage cheese and fruits (I chose frozen raspberry and cherries for this picture) to this granola to make a complete meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa and Peanut Butter Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls were a success on a backcountry ski trip! They are low-fat and are packed with carbohydrates for energy during the long grueling skin up sections.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats ⅓ cup (80 ml) powdered peanut butter 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa  Preparation  Bring dates and water to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 cup roasted hazelnuts ¼ cup cocoa  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Bar</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-bar/</guid>
      <description>Perfect bars to fuel your winter adventures! They stay soft even at freezing temperature, which make them easy to eat during a snowy day. Their subtle coffee aroma along with powerful chocolate flavors will make you wish you brought more of these bars with you! Please note, there is about 20mg of caffeine per bar, which is the equivalent of about ¼ of a cup of brewed coffee.
Ingredients  1 ½ cup (375 ml) pitted dates, cut in small pieces 1 cup (250 ml) water 2 tbsp (30 ml) instant coffee 1 tsp (5 ml) baking powder 1 cup (250 ml) quick oats ½ cup (125 ml) whole wheat flour ½ cup (125 ml) skim milk powder ¼ cup (60 ml) sweetened shredded coconut ⅓ cup (80 ml) cocoa powder 1 pinch of salt ⅔ cup (160 ml) semi-sweet chocolate chips 1 tbsp (15 ml) unsalted butter  Preparation  Combine the dates and water in a small pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange, Dark Chocolate and Sweet Potato Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/orange-choc-sweet-potato-muffins/</guid>
      <description>These delicious muffins are a good option for breakfast-on-the-go when driving to the mountains early in the morning. Bring a fruit and a portion of milk or drinkable yogurt for a more complete breakfast!
Alternatively, these muffins can be a good snack for a low-intensity training.
Ingredients  1 small sweet potato, peeled and cut in medium pieces 1 cup (250 ml) all-purpose flour 1 cup (250 ml) oats bran (taste more delicate than wheat bran but still high in fiber) 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin and Spices Cookies</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-spices-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pumpkin-spices-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Sweet and satisfying, these cookies will be the perfect partners for your next hiking or long bike ride. Rich in carbohydrate, they will provide the fuel you need for your next outdoor adventure. Their protein and fiber content will make you fill full until your next stop.
Vincent and I tested these cookies on a climb of Mt. St. Helens, WA. The cookies were even better on the mountain than in my kitchen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini, Lemon and Blueberries Muffins</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/zucchini-lemon-blueberries-muffin/</guid>
      <description>If you have a garden that produces an impressive quantity of zucchinis and that you don’t know what to do with them at this point, this recipe is for you!
As usual, I tested this recipe in the outdoor. Since it makes a dozen, I brought them on several adventures: from rock climbing to hiking on different trails in Washington State.
Sweet and satisfying these muffins make a good snack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>