<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vegan on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/vegan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vegan on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/vegan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Morrocan Apricot Chickpeas</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/morrocan_apricot_chickpea/</guid>
      <description>Warm, comforting and sweet, this dish will transport your taste buds somewhere else. Perfect to add variety to your backpacking meals. And you will not believe that this vegan recipe contains 28g of proteins and 6.1 mg of iron (thanks to the dried apricots for this nice contribution!)
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry couscous salt and pepper, to taste 1 cup (250 ml) dehydrated fast cooking chickpeas ¼ cup (60 ml) dried onion flakes ½ cup (125 ml) dehydrated apricots, chopped in small cubes ½ tsp (2 ml) ground coriander seeds ½ tsp (2 ml) ground ginger ½ tsp (2 ml) cumin ¼ tsp (1 ml) cinnamon ¼ tsp (1 ml) paprika ¼ tsp (1 ml) salt 1 pinch of cayenne pepper ⅓ cup (80 ml) roasted almonds  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple candied pecans and apples with sea salt sprinkles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/maple-candied-pecans/</guid>
      <description>The fanciest of trail mixes, this mix combines sweet and salty flavors for a premium snack on the trail. It is a good option for these cold outdoor adventures when maximizing the energy density (calories/weight) is a must. It also does taste super good on day snowshoeing or backcountry skiing adventures! Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) gluten-free puffed rice 1 cup (250 ml) pecans ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ¼ cup (60 ml) real maple syrup ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asian Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/asian-peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This recipe includes the peanut trio for real fans: chopped peanuts, real peanut butter and powdered peanut butter. Super high in protein and energy, this recipe will satisfy the most hungry backpacker. Enjoy!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 (5.3 oz) 150 g thick rice noodles (like the ones for pad thai) ½ cup (125 ml) textured vegetable protein (TVP)* ½ cup (125 ml) mix of dried bell peppers ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried wakame seaweed** ¼ cup ( 60 ml) dried carrots 2 tbsp (30 ml) dried chives 2 tsp (10 ml) ground ginger 1 tsp (5 ml) pepper flakes ½ cup (125 ml) powdered peanut butter ½ cup (125 ml) chopped peanuts 2 tbsp (30 ml) sesame seeds 1 tbsp (15 ml) brown sugar 4 individual (7 ml) packages of soy sauce 2 oz (60 ml) peanut butter (I used 2 individual packages of Justin’s)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowls to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/mocha-energy-ball/</guid>
      <description>These energy balls have a subtil coffee taste that will please the coffee lovers but are sweet enough to please the non coffee drinkers. This snack kept me going on a recent climb of Mt.Rainier that was longer than expected. I am not sure how I managed to save one energy ball to take a picture at the top&amp;hellip;
Ingredients  ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa 1 ½ tsp (7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**  * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa and Peanut Butter Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cocoa-pb-ball/</guid>
      <description>Sweet to perfection, these energy balls were a success on a backcountry ski trip! They are low-fat and are packed with carbohydrates for energy during the long grueling skin up sections.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¾ cup (175 ml) chopped dates ½ cup (125 ml) water 1 cup (250 ml) old-fashioned oats ⅓ cup (80 ml) powdered peanut butter 2 tbsp (30 ml) cocoa  Preparation  Bring dates and water to boil and let simmer for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 cup roasted hazelnuts ¼ cup cocoa  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>