<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>No Bake on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/no-bake/</link>
    <description>Recent content in No Bake on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/no-bake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry and Vanilla Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/blueberry-vanilla-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Dessert is always good and even more on the trail. Add 10g of protein to your meal by adding this delicious dessert. Top this pudding with fresh blueberries found on the side of the trail, when in season, for extra nutrients and antioxidants. Replace powdered skim milk instead by full-fat milk for extra calories.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) dried blueberries 1 large graham cookie, crushed 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate and Raspberries Dirt Pudding</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/dirt_pudding_choc_rasp/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ¼ cup (60 ml) freeze dried raspberries 2 Oreo cookies, crushed 3 tbsp. (45 ml) instant chocolate pudding mix 3 tbsp. (45 ml) powdered skim milk  Equipment  Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the bag, no judgement here!) Spork or spoon  Before trip  Mix in plastic bag #1: raspberries and Oreo cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/pina-colada-energy-balls/</guid>
      <description>These sweet energy balls will transport you on a beach with palm trees and white sand! The sugars contained in this snack will provide quick energy to keep you hiking whether you are on the beach or on a snow-covered mountain!
Ingredients  ½ cup (125 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried and sweetened pineapples ½ cup (125 ml) roasted cashews* ½ cup (125 ml) sweetened shredded coconut, divided in 2 equal parts**  * I used coconut cashews from Trader Joe’s to get extra coconut taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Blueberry, Almond and Chia Seeds Bars</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/apple-blue-almond-bar/</guid>
      <description>Lack of energy after a few hours of skiing? Whether you are the type of people to earn their turns or to enjoy a ride up in chair lift, try these bars! With 20g of carbohydrates and 2.5g of fiber per portion, these bars will keep your energy level high!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 cup (250 ml) pitted dates ½ cup (125 ml) dried blueberries ½ cup (125 ml) dried apples ½ cup (125 ml) almond 2 tbsp (30 ml) chia seeds  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig, Hazelnut and Chocolate Energy Balls</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/fig-chocolate-ball/</guid>
      <description>Hazelnut and chocolate: can we have a better pairing? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip; These balls are perfect on a ski trips or winter hike.
Ingredients  1 cup pitted dates 1 cup dried figs 1 cup roasted hazelnuts ¼ cup cocoa  Preparation  Combine all ingredients in food processor. Blend until it reaches the desired texture. This can take a few minutes. Roll dough into balls. Chill for at least 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>