<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lunch on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/tags/lunch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lunch on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/tags/lunch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Chicken Chowder</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/sw-chicken-chowder/</guid>
      <description>This chowder with southwest notes makes a consistent meal with 40g of protein per serving. Perfect to warm up on chilly evenings.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 1 tbsp (15 ml) dried onion flakes 3 tbsp (45 ml) dried bell peppers(I used a mix of green and red peppers) 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried corn 1 cup (250 ml) freeze dried chicken 1 tbsp (15 ml) chicken broth powder ¼ tsp (1 ml) cayenne pepper ¼ tsp (1 ml) dried thyme ¼ tsp (1 ml) black pepper 2 tbsp (30 ml) ghee ¾ cup (175 ml) whole milk powder 2 ½ tbsp (37 ml) cornstarch  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miso and Edamame Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/miso_edamame_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup makes a perfect appetizer and kick-starts the rehydration process after a long day on the trail.
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 individual packs of instant miso soup 60 g (2 oz) rice noodles 1 package (20g) freeze dried edamame  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 1 liter (4 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley and Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/barley_mushroom_soup/</guid>
      <description>This super-easy-to-make soup is the perfect way to rehydrate after a long day in the outdoors. It does not contain enough energy (only 112 calories) for a dinner but is the perfect appetizer!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 2 tbsp. (30 ml) 10 minute barley 1 tsp. (5 ml) dried parsley 2 tbsp. (30 ml) dried carrots 3 tbsp. (45 ml) freeze dried white mushrooms 1&amp;frasl;2 cube of beef broth (for the equivalent of 1 cup of broth)  Equipment  Stove + fuel Pot large enough for 2 liters (8 cups) Wooden spoon to mix Bowl to eat (you could always eat directly in the pot, no judgement here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Cheese and Ham Bread</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cheese-ham-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/cheese-ham-bread/</guid>
      <description>A slice of bread that contains 18g of proteins? Yeap, and it tastes delicious! This bread is moist but dense enough to travel well in a backpack. For those who worry that making bread is complicated, this recipe will prove you the contrary! The fat from the cheese keeps this bread moist for 4 to 5 days if well wrapped.
Ingredients  8.8 oz (250 g) black forest ham, cut in small cubes 1 tbsp (15 ml) olive oil 3½ cup (875 ml) all-purpose flour ¾ tsp (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable and Vermicelli Soup</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/recipes/vegetable_vermicelli_soup/</guid>
      <description>This soup will warm you up on chilly backpack nights and help you rehydrate after a long day on the trail. This soup is also the perfect appetizer for a multi-course backpack meal!
Ingredients Note: This recipe contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
 ½ cup (125 ml) dry vermicelli, chopped in small pieces (or soup pasta) 5 tsp. (25 ml) chicken broth powder 3 tbsp. (45 ml) dried spinach 3 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>