<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product-reviews on Gourmet Hiking</title>
    <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product-reviews on Gourmet Hiking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Gourmet Hiking; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 21:07:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Camp Cuisine Classic Hummus</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/camp-cuisine-hummus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/camp-cuisine-hummus/</guid>
      <description>Note: This menu contains affiliate links. You can read my disclosure here.
Taste 3 / 5 Bland when eaten on its own. Add sundried tomatoes, olives, dried herbs or spices to add flavor.
Nutrition analysis 4.5 / 5 Pros: Relatively simple list of ingredients. Half of a package provides 8g of fiber and 16g of protein, which makes a good foundation for a satisfying meal on the trail.
Cons: With 100 mg of sodium by 2 tbsp of prepared hummus, the amount of sodium can easily reach high levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krave Chili Lime Beef Jerky</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/krave-beef-jerky-chili-lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/krave-beef-jerky-chili-lime/</guid>
      <description>Taste 3 / 5 Subtle notes of lime for the first bite but for the following bites, it seems like the spicyness is the only thing noticeable. Texture is ok.
Nutrition analysis 3.5 / 5 Pros: Low in fat (1.5g/oz). Sodium (380mg/oz) is lower than in other jerkys. Ingredient list relatively easy to understand.
Cons: more carbohydrates than protein in a meat-based product!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunt&#39;s Tomato Paste</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/hunts-tomato-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/hunts-tomato-paste/</guid>
      <description>Taste 5 / 5 Tomato pasta in purée. No added herbs or seasoning. It is very versatile and can be used in a lot of recipes on the trail: pasta sauce, mexican rice, chili, stews and soups.
Nutrition analysis 4.5 / 5 Pros: Low in sodium (25mg/ pouch) and high in potassium (420 mg/pouch). It looks like there is no added sugar (according to the ingredient list). High fiber content (3g/pouch).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmega Mint Crisp</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oatmega-mint-crisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oatmega-mint-crisp/</guid>
      <description>Taste 4.5 / 5 Nice texture that stays soft even at freezing temperature. Good taste of chocolate and mint. Hardly noticeable taste of whey
Nutrition analysis 4 / 5 Pros: High content of fiber (7g/bar), low simple sugars (5g/bar) and high content in protein (14g/bar) which helps with satiety. It makes it a good snack for low to moderate intensity activities. Whey comes from grass-fed cows and fish oil from responsibly-caught fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oberto’s Applewood Smoked Bacon Jerky</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oberto-applewood-smoked-bacon-jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/oberto-applewood-smoked-bacon-jerky/</guid>
      <description>Taste 4.5 / 5 Authentic taste of bacon with a nice applewood smoke twist to it. Although the jerky is pretty dry, it is not too tough to eat. This jerky is good to eat on its own but could also be a good addition to dishes cooked on the trail such as egg scrambles or alfredo pasta.
Nutrition analysis 2.5 / 5 Pros: High in protein (12g/oz) for a jerky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tillamook Country Smoker Teriyaki Meat Stick</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/tillamook-teriyaki-meat-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/tillamook-teriyaki-meat-stick/</guid>
      <description>Taste 2.5 / 5 Nothing exceptional here. The taste reminded me of hot-dogs… Inside texture is soft, the outside layer being a little rough.
Nutrition analysis 2 / 5 Pros: not much to say here… The first ingredients are beef and pork!
Cons: Long list of ingredients that required advanced nutrition knowledge to understand. High in sodium (533mg/oz). High in fat (8g/oz) and relatively high in saturated fat (3g/oz). Relatively low in protein (5g/oz) for meat-based product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tillamook Smoked &amp; Dried Beef Steak Cuts Teriyaki</title>
      <link>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/smoked-dried-beef-steak-cuts-teriyaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 21:07:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//gourmethiking.com/product-reviews/smoked-dried-beef-steak-cuts-teriyaki/</guid>
      <description>Taste 3.5 / 5 The thick pieces change from the usual thin sliced jerky. Texture is soft. Taste does not offer anything out of the ordinary: sweet soy sauce&amp;hellip;
Nutrition analysis 4 / 5 Pros: Ingredients’ list is short and very easy to understand. More protein than carbohydrates, which is what we are looking for in a jerky!
Cons: Sodium (450 mg/oz) is pretty high.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>